Car 3 1, Ashton apartment building, third floor.
31号车，阿斯顿公寓楼， 三楼。
Cars 3 1 and 36, 926 Ford Street.
31号车和36号车，福特大街926号。
Cars 3 1 and 36, 926 Ford Street. Officers standing there now.
31号车和36号车，福特大街926号。 现在警官们已经站在那里了。
Attention, car 7 1.
注意，71号车。
Holdup, Hotel de Paris, Camden Square south.
抢劫，巴黎宾馆， 坎登广场南端。
Holdup, Hotel de Paris.
抢劫，巴黎宾馆。
Armed suspect, tall man, Caucasian, wearing a dark suit and soft hat.
武装嫌疑犯，高个子，高加索人， 穿深色西装，戴软帽。
This is car 7 1 . Roger.
这是71号车。罗杰。
Gus.
戈斯。
-What time this punk come in? -I don't watch the cIock.
-这家伙是几点进来的？ -我没看表。
-I own the joint. -No gun.
-这是我的店。 -没有枪。
I'II search the joint.
我要搜查这家店。
-You got a warrant? -Look, why don't you cooperate.
-你有搜查证吗？ -听着，你为什么不合作一点？
-Get a warrant. -Take him in.
-拿搜查证来吧。 -把他带走。
-On what? -We'II book him on vag.
-为什么？ -我们把他按流浪罪登记。
AII right. Come on, you.
好吧。过来，你。
Come on.
过来。
Smith, KarI Anton, age 37.
史密斯，卡尔・安顿，年龄：37。
Arrested 6 p.m. Iast night.
昨晚6点被逮捕。
Phoned poIice station stating he had murdered Mrs. Catherine Smith.
曾给警察局打电话说 他谋杀了凯瑟琳・史密斯夫人。
DoIdy, WiIIiam, age 22.
多迪，威廉，年龄：22。
Possession narcotics. Occupation, cIerk.
私藏毒品。 职业：店员。
No previous record.
没有前科。
Attempt suicide Iast night with necktie.
昨天晚上试图用领带自杀。
HandIey, WiIIiam Trevor, aIias Dix HandIey, age 36.
汉德莱，威廉・特莱乌， 别名迪克斯・汉德莱，年龄：36。
Born Kentucky. Occupation, none.
生于肯塔基州。 职业：无业。
Arrested 1 937, iIIegaI possession firearm. Sentence, one to five.
1937年被捕，非法持有枪支。 判决，一到五年。
Escaped state prison, 1 939. Arrested 1 940, reIeased 1 941 .
1939年越狱。 1940被捕，1941年获释。
That's enough.
够了。
WeII, do you see the man who puIIed the stickup Iast night?
好，你看到昨晚抢劫的那个人了吗？
-I don't know. -What do you mean, you don't know?
-我不知道。 -你什么意思，你不知道？
He had a hat on.
他戴了一顶帽子。
Put on your hats.
戴上你们的帽子。
WeII?
好？
He was taII, you say. He had on a brown suit and a wide-brim hat.
你说过他是高个子。他穿一件棕外套， 戴一顶宽边帽。
AII right. Don't you see him?
好吧。你看见他了吗？
WeII, come on. Is that him?
好，来吧。是那个吗？
No, it isn't him.
不，不是他。
-Okay. -That's aII.
-好吧。 -散会。
Lieutenant Ditrich, commissioner wants to see you in his office right away.
迪特里奇中尉，专员想 现在在他的办公室见你。
Sit down, Iieutenant.
坐下，中尉。
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你，先生。
Thirty-nine thefts, 33 burgIaries, 1 8 robberies, seven assauIts...
39个小偷，33件盗窃案， 18起抢劫，7起强奸...
...five moraIs offenses in the past 30 days.
...五起道德侵犯， 在过去的30天里。
Quite a record, even for the 4th Precinct.
真是创记录啊， 即使对第四区来说也是。
We know the guy who's been puIIing most of the stickups.
我们知道那个做了 很多起抢劫案的家伙。
Name's Dix HandIey.
他的名字是迪克斯・汉德莱。
He was in the show-up this morning, but our witness got coId feet and backed down.
他今天早晨到场了，但 我们的证人临阵退缩了
-What can you do? -Lock up the witness! Scare him worse!
-我能怎么办？ -把证人关起来！吓唬他！
It's your job, knowing what to do.
那是你的工作，你应该知道做什么。
The onIy merchants safe from harm in your precinct...
在你的管区里唯一不受伤害的商人...
...are those who take wagers on the horses.
...就是那些赌马的人。
I wanna know why those parIors are stiII operating.
我想知道为什么那些接待室还在工作？
I cIose them down, but they open up again.
我把它们关了，但他们又开张了。
You don't cIose them hard enough. Rip out the phones, smash up the furniture!
你关的还不够严。 切断电话线，砸烂那些家具！
PeopIe Iike to bet the horses, and just because the Iaw says--
人们喜欢赌马， 就是因为法律规定--
I don't want your opinion of the Iaw.
我不想听你对法律的看法。
-Is that aII, sir? -No, that's not aII.
-完了吗，先生？ -不，还没完。
-Where's Erwin Riedenschneider? -I'm waiting to hear on that, sir.
-艾尔温・林登施耐德在哪里？ -我正在等消息，先生。
You don't know where he is, do you?
你不知道他在哪里，是吗？
No, but we ought to get a word from our stooIies.
是的，但我们应该能从我们的密探那里得到消息。
It was aII dumped in your Iap.
这件事完全由你负责。
He Ieft prison yesterday at 1 2 noon, took a train for this city, time of arrivaI, 3:1 7.
他昨天中午12点离开监狱，坐一趟火车 来这个城市，到达时间是，3:17。
AII you had to do was stay with him for 24 hours.
你所要做的就是和他呆在一起24小时。
If he didn't register, Iock him up. What happens?
如果他没有登记，就把他关起来。 而实际发生了什么？
He Ioses you five bIocks from the depot, and a dangerous criminaI...
他从车站起就摆脱了你五个街区， 一个危险的罪犯...
...is at Iarge in this city.
...在这个城市里是很严重的。
Two men on that detaiI ought to get medaIs for dumbness.
那两个具体负责的人应该获得笨蛋奖章。
They were assigned by you. You shouId get one too.
他们是你的手下。 你也应该得到一块。
Ditrich, I can do three things about you:
迪特里奇, 我有三个选择处理你：
I can reduce you to patroIman, send you down to Five Corners.
我可以把你降为巡警， 把你送到五角街去。
I can bring you up for triaI on charges of incompetence.
也可以以你不称职为理由报告上级。
Or I can give you one more chance to make good on your responsibiIities.
或者还可以再给你一次机会， 希望你尽好你的职责。
I think that'II be the greatest punishment of aII.
我想那会是所有惩罚里最好的一种。
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你，先生。
There's the number you're Iooking for, but it's dark.
这就是你要找到门牌号， 但是太黑了。
You want me to wait?
你要我在这里等吗？
I wouIdn't go parading around this neighborhood with a suitcase.
我可不会在这样的地方 拎着一只皮箱四处乱走。
Some of these young punks might cIip you just to get a cIean shirt.
这些小流氓们会把你打倒， 只为了抢一件干净的衬衫。
-Yeah? -I want to see Cobby.
-什么事？ -我来找考比。
-Who are you? -Just say Doc is here...
-你是谁？ -就说博士...
...and wouId Iike to see him.
...想要见他。
Wait here. You'd better be on the Iegit, paI.
等一下。 你最好有正当理由，伙计。
WeII, where the deviI is he?
好，他到底在哪里？
I'm a busy man. What do you want?
我很忙。 你想要什么？
I just got out today.
我今天刚出来。
Oh, so that's it.
哦，那就对了。
I'm tired of you guys putting a bite on me.
我已经厌倦了你们这些吸血鬼。
-I'm no bank. -I got a proposition for you.
-我不是银行。 -我有一笔生意给你。
AII you guys have.
你们这帮人都有生意。
-Maybe you didn't get who I was. -I ain't never seen you before. What is it?
-可能你还不知道我是谁。 -我以前从来没见过你。你是谁？
Maybe you've heard of me. The Professor? Or Herr Doctor, maybe.
可能你们听说过我。 教授？或者也许博士先生。
You mean, you are Riedenschneider?
你是说你是林登施耐德？
WeII, why didn't you say so?
哦，你怎么不早说？
Come on in, Doc. Come on in.
快进来，博士。进来。
Sit down, Doc. Sit down.
请坐，博士。请坐。
-Have a drink? -Nothing to drink.
-喝点什么吗？ -什么也不喝。
I got out of the habit behind the waIIs.
我在监狱里逐渐放弃了这个习惯。
That's aII it is, a habit.
就是这样，一个习惯。
WeII, here's to the drink habit, the onIy one I got that don't get me into troubIe.
好吧，向喝酒的习惯敬一杯， 只是一杯，不会给我带来麻烦。
WeII, Doc. What's on your mind?
好，博士。你有什么想法？
I got a proposition. A big one.
我有一个生意。一个大生意。
-How big is big? -Too big for you, Cobby.
-多大？ -对你来说太大了，考比。
Now, wait, Doc. I don't Iike to brag, but I'm doing aII right.
好，等等，博士。我不喜欢吹牛， 但我现在过的很好。
Making book. I'm in the chips.
做庄。挣不少钱。
What kind of proposition is it?
什么样的生意？
A pIan for a caper. And it's a good one.
一个不法行为的计划。 一个很好的计划。
I couId seII it for $ 1 00,000 on the open market...
我可以把它在公开市场上卖10万美元...
...but that wouId be throwing money away.
...但那简直就是在扔钱。
-I prefer to execute it myseIf and make-- -How much?
-我更喜欢我自己来做，那样可以挣-- -多少钱？
HaIf a miIIion doIIars.
五十万美元。
Maybe even more.
可能更多。
I wiII have to do a IittIe checking, as the pIan is some years oId...
我需要做一点小检查， 因为这个计划有点年头了...
...but not much checking. Not much.
...但不会是太大的检查。不大。
I need roughIy 50,000 to operate.
我需要大约五万来运作。
Fifty thousand?
五万？
-No, no, no. I don't see. -Of course.
-不，不，不。我不明白。 -当然。
I thought maybe Mr. Emmerich....
我想或许艾默瑞先生....
What do you know about Mr. Emmerich?
你对艾默瑞先生了解多少？
OnIy what I heard in the waIIs...
只有我在大墙里面听到的那些...
...that he has money to invest and that the way to get to him is through you.
...他有钱来投资，而找到他的办法就是通过你。
-If my information is not correct-- -Correct, sure. Sure. It's correct.
-如果我的情报不准确-- -准确，当然。当然。是准确的。
I just never thought of Mr. Emmerich in connection with this kind of deaI.
我只是从没想过艾默瑞先生 和这种事情有关系。
Excuse me a minute. I'II be right back.
稍等我一下。我马上回来。
-HeIIo, Dix. What do you want? -I wanna make a bet.
-喂，迪克斯。你想要什么？ -我想去赌一把。
-WeII? -Your man says you got to okay it.
-唔？ -你的人说你会同意的。
-What are you in for? -2300 and some.
-你想要多少？ -2300左右。
Okay. Your tab's good for 2500...
好。你还可以借2500...
...but that's the Iimit. Either pick a winner or pay me when you get that far.
...但那是极限了。或者赢一场， 或者当你到那个数的时候还我。
Don't bone me!
别挑剔我！
-I'm not-- -Did I ever weIsh?
-没有-- -我赖过账吗？
-Nobody said you did-- -You just boned me.
-没人说你赖过-- -你刚刚挑剔我了。
I'm not asking you any favors. I'II go get you your 2300 right now.
我不再求你帮任何忙。 我现在就去还你那2300。
Now, Dix. Now, Dix, Iisten. WiII you have a drink? Come on.
好，迪克斯。好，迪克斯，听着。 你想喝点什么吗？来吧。
Come on. Come back here. Have a drink, wiII you?
来吧。回来这里。 喝点吧，喝吗？
Can you beat that?
你能打败它吗？
-Where does he come off, bIowing a fuse? -Who is he?
-他是从哪儿冒出来的，从天而降？ -他是谁？
A smaIItime hooIigan, who's crazy for horses.
一个无关紧要的流氓， 发疯似地喜欢赌马。
My book beats him and beats him, he keeps coming back for more.
他在我这儿输了一回又一回， 他还回来接着赌。
Say, Doc...
说吧，博士...
...I forgot on account of that big tramp.
...我忘了那个流浪者的账户了。
I spoke to Mr. Emmerich on the phone. He's gonna meet us Iater tonight.
我和艾默瑞先生在电话里说了。 他今天晚上晚点来见我们。
He's giving a party at his house in town for a bunch of sweIIs...
他正在他城里的房子为 一些重要人物举办一个宴会...
...but he'II be at another address Iater on.
...但他晚点会到另外一个地方。
A man Iike Emmerich has got more than one pIace to hang his hat.
象艾默瑞这样的人总是狡兔三窟的。
Smart cat. Never does a Iick of work, stays out aII night, sIeeps aII day.
聪明的猫。一点活也不干， 整夜在外游逛，白天睡觉。
What's a big, dirty cat doing at an eating joint?
一只大脏猫在饭馆里能干什么？
I run over one every time I get a chance.
每次只要一有机会我就会赶跑一只。
PeopIe feeding cats, and some kids haven't got enough to eat.
有些孩子还吃不饱饭，还有人养猫。
You gonna buy that magazine?
你要买那本杂志吗？
Why shouId I? I seen aII the dames in it aIready.
为什么？ 我已经看完了里面所有的女人。
Wanna make something of it?
想拿它做点什么吗？
-You're a IittIe off your beat. -How do you mean, Humpty Dumpty?
-你有点跑调了。 -你什么意思，哼哼唧唧？
I mean, you don't beIong around here.
我的意思是说，你根本就不应该在这里。
You're just passing through, onIy not fast enough.
你路过这里，只是还不够快。
If I ever see you running over a cat, I'II kick your teeth out.
如果我再看见你赶一只猫， 我会打的你满地找牙。
I'd take you apart if you were about a foot taIIer and straightened up a IittIe.
如果你个子再高一点，腰背再 直一点，我就找你单挑了。
Suppose you want your heater back.
你想要回你的枪？
WeII, you ain't gonna get it. How about that?
哦，你不会得到它。 怎么样？
-Quit kidding, Gus. -I mean it.
-别开玩笑了，戈斯。 -我是认真的。
Go on, get sore. Smack me down.
继续，生气吧。把我打倒。
-You know I wouIdn't do that. -Look, Dix...
-你知道我不会那么做。 -听着，迪克斯...
...take my advice and knock off for a whiIe.
...听我的建议， 停一段时间。
The happiness boys are on a rampage. Headquarters has given them the push.
警察们发怒了。 上头给他们很大的压力。
-I can't afford to knock off. -Oh, stop worrying. I'II stake you.
-我停不下来。 -哦，别担心。我来担保你。
-Yeah? I need 2300. -What?
-是吗？我需要2300. -什么？
-Something I just gotta take care of. -Cobby, maybe?
-一些我需要处理的事情。 -考比，可能？
WeII, Iet him sweat. It'II do him good. Cobby can spare a few pounds.
好吧，让他出汗去吧。那样对他有好处。 考比可以借一些钱。
You can't owe money to a guy Iike him...
你不能欠他那样的人的钱...
...a IittIe Ioudmouth who bones you when he isn't even trying to.
...他有点大嘴，不经意间就会挑剔你。
I don't get you, Dix.
我不明白你的意思，迪克斯。
I just can't be in Cobby's debt and keep my seIf-respect.
我没法欠考比的钱，同时还保持我的自尊。
AII right.
好吧。
I got a grand put away. You can have that.
我有一千放在别处。 你可以拿到那些。
Maybe I can dig up 1 300 more.
可能我还能弄到另外的1300。
-I guess it's aII right to owe me, huh? -I guess.
-我想欠我的钱没问题，呃？ -我想也是。
Yeah. It's just my Iuck.
是的。真是我的运气。
WeII, I'II get it tomorrow or bust a gut.
好，我会明天拿到， 否则就破产了。
In the meantime, stay away from the bouIevard, especiaIIy at night.
同时，离大路远点，尤其是晚上。
By the way, they knocked over the CIub RegaI.
顺便说一句，他们关闭 了里戈俱乐部。
-Wasn't that where DoII worked? -Yeah.
-那不是朵尔工作的地方吗？ -是的。
It's coming in bunches, it Iooks Iike.
同时关了好多，好象是的。
Go home, Dix. Stay home.
回家吧，迪克斯。呆在家里。
Don't get your fIag at haIf-mast. Remember, you stiII got oId Gus.
先别为自己降半旗。 记住，你还有老戈斯。
Thirteen hundred? You must be crazy.
一千三？你一定疯了。
For Dix? What do I care for that hooIigan?
给迪克斯？我管那个流氓干什么？
I'd Iike to heIp you out, Gus, but I got mouths to feed...
我非常想帮你，戈斯， 但我得养家糊口...
...and rent to pay and aII that stuff.
...还有房租，各种各样的帐单。
Why don't you wise up, you wise guy?
你为什么不放聪明点， 聪明的家伙？
You're a Iow-down scum.
你是一个卑鄙的人渣。
A Iow-down, dirty scum, to taIk to me Iike that.
一个卑鄙，肮脏的人渣， 敢跟我这样说话。
Look, Gus.
听着，戈斯。
I guess I can make it, aII right.
我想我可以弄到，好吧。
-Yeah? -Dix, it's me, Doll.
-谁？ -迪克斯, 是我，朵尔。
DoII?
朵尔?
Hi, honey.
嗨，亲爱的。
Come on in.
进来吧。
-CIose the door. -WeII, sure, Dix. Sure.
-关上门。 -好，当然，迪克斯。当然。
I'm awfuI sorry to bother you, honey, but....
我非常抱歉来打扰你， 亲爱的，但是....
DoII, if you're gonna smoke, you gotta Iearn to carry matches.
朵尔，如果你想抽烟，你必须记得带火柴。
DoII, what are you crying about?
朵尔，你在哭什么？
Nothing--
没什么--
I'm sorry.
对不起。
I'm sorry, Dix.
对不起，迪克斯。
I don't know what I was thinking about, bothering you at this time of the night.
我不知道我在想什么， 这么晚了还来打扰你。
I'II just run aIong.
我马上就走。
Gus toId me the CIub RegaI got knocked over.
戈斯告诉我说里戈俱乐部被关闭了。
Yeah. Can you imagine, raiding the RegaI? The cops must have aII gone crazy.
是的。你能想象吗，搜查里戈？ 警察们一定全疯了。
So it's a cIip joint. So what?
那就是一个夜总会。那又怎么样呢？
And it wouId have to happen on pay night.
而且还一定要在发薪日搞。
-How about a drink? -Hey, don't care if I do.
-喝点什么吗？ -嘿，别介意，我不喝。
One of my eyeIashes is coming off.
我的一只隐形眼镜掉出来了。
Were you Iocked out of your room?
你是被锁在你的屋外了吗？
How'd you guess?
你是怎么猜到的？
Here's how.
这样猜到的。
Dix, if it wouIdn't be too much troubIe, couId I stay here a coupIe of days?
迪克斯，如果没有太大麻烦的话， 我能在这里呆两天吗？
Just a day or two.
只是一天或者两天。
AII right. Stay if you want to, but don't you go getting any ideas, DoII.
好吧。如果你愿意就呆吧， 但你不去想点办法吗，朵尔？
Everything is here, from the observed routine of the personneI...
所有东西都在这里，从人员观察路径...
...to the aIarm system, the type of Iocks on doors...
...到警报系统，门锁类型...
...the age and condition of the main safe and so forth, so forth.
...主保险柜的年头和状况等等等等。
Take my word for it, Mr. Emmerich. This is a ripe pIum ready to faII.
相信我，艾默瑞先生。 这是一个成熟的果实，唾手可得。
My friend, according to the boys, aII takes are easy...
我的朋友，按照孩子们的话说， 所有获利都是容易的...
...but as a Iawyer, I make Iots of money getting them out of jaiI.
...但作为一个律师来说，我可以通过把 他们从监狱里放出来挣很多的钱。
PIease, Mr. Emmerich. Perhaps you know my reputation.
拜托，艾默瑞先生。 可能你知道我的声望。
I've engineered some very big things.
我曾经操作过一些非常大的事件。
That's a fact, Mr. Emmerich. Doc here is tops.
的确如此，艾默瑞先生。 博士是顶尖的。
Am I to understand you gathered this information before doing your Iast stretch?
我是不是可以认为你获取这些 信息是在你最后一次入狱之前？
That is correct. I was ready to begin operations...
是的。 我已经准备好要开始操作了...
...and the cops grabbed me for an oId caper I'd aImost forgotten about.
...警察把我抓住了， 因为一件我都几乎忘记的老案子。
The AdeIphia Finance caper.
阿道夫财务案。
You took them for 1 60,000, didn't you, Doc?
你偷了他们16万， 对吗，博士？
A hundred and fifty-eight.
十五万八。
You reaIIy beIieve there's a miIIion in this thing?
你真的相信这件事情有一百万吗？
-Maybe even more. -You mean by that...
-可能更多。 -你是说...
...that the take wiII be worth haIf a miIIion to us in actuaI cash?
...我们真能得到五十万吗？
You know as weII as I do that in no case wiII a fence...
你跟我知道的一样清楚， 没有一个买家...
-...give you more than 50 percent. -That's right, sir.
-...会给你超过50%。 -是的，先生。
-WeII, what are your main probIems? -There are three.
-好吧，你的主要问题是什么？ -有三个。
Money to operate, personneI and finaIIy, the disposing of the take.
做事的钱，人， 最后还有获利的处理。
No troubIe about the first, eh?
第一项没问题，呃？
Wait a minute. This remains to be seen.
等一下。 我们以后会知道的。
The heIpers wiII be paid off Iike housepainters.
助手们的工资是死工资。
They'II be toId nothing about the size of the take.
他们完全不知道行动的大小。
Sometimes, men get greedy.
有时候人会变得很贪婪。
-WeII, how many heIpers do you need? -OnIy three.
-好吧，你需要几个助手？ -只要三个。
A box man.
一个锁匠。
Him, we pay most. Maybe $25,000.
他，我们给的最多。 可能25,000美元。
I got a guy for you. Louis CiaveIIi. Best box man west of Chicago.
我有一个合适的人选。路易斯・蔡弗利。 芝加哥西部最好的锁匠。
Expert mechanic. Been in some very big capers.
机械专家。 干过大事的。
From what I hear, he can open a safe Iike the back of a watch. OnIy, he costs.
就我所知，他打开一个保险柜 就象开表盖一样容易。只不过，他要价不菲。
Then we need a topnotch driver, in case of a rumbIe.
第二，我们需要一个最好的司机，以备万一。
He shouId get 1 0,000.
他可以得到10,000美元。
And finaIIy, sad to say, we need a hooIigan.
最后，很不幸地说， 我们需要一个流氓。
Most of these feIIas are drug addicts. They're a no-good Iot.
这些家伙大部分都是吸毒者。 他们没有一点长处。
VioIence is aII they know, but they are, unfortunateIy, necessary.
暴力是他们唯一知道的， 但不幸的是，他们是必需的。
For a more or Iess reIiabIe man, I'd say 1 5,000.
对一个或多或少可靠的人， 我愿意付15,000。
WeII, that's 50,000 in aII.
好，总共是50,000。
How...?
这个...？
How's this take to be handIed?
这些东西怎么处理？
Get in touch with the best fences in the Midwest...
和中西部最好的买家联系...
...and deaI with whoever makes the highest offer.
...和出价最高的人交易。
Maybe no one fence can handIe the whoIe thing.
可能没有一个买家能接这么大的买卖。
In that case, we deaI with two or three.
如果是那样，我们和两个或者三个进行交易。
HaIf a miIIion, eh?
五十万，呃？
I....
我....
I'm just thinking.
我在想。
If I decide to go into this thing, I....
如果我决定加入这件事情，我....
I, myseIf, I might handIe the--
我，我自己，我可能可以--
You, a fence, Mr. Emmerich?
你，一个买家，艾默瑞先生？
Oh, no, no, Cobby. Not exactIy.
哦，不，不，考比。不完全如此。
But your proposition Iooks pretty good. I'd Iike to see the most made of it.
你的生意看起来很不错。 我愿意了解的更多一些。
Oh, I suppose a feIIa shouId stick to his own trade...
哦，我想一个人应该忠于自己的生意...
...but I know some big men that might not be averse to a deaI Iike this...
...但我认识一些大人物，他们可能不反对 这样的一笔买卖...
...if they're properIy approached.
...如果能和他们正确地打交道的话。
HighIy respectabIe men, I might add.
非常值得尊敬的人物，可以这么说。
So why don't you Iet me see what I can do before you Iook for a fence.
那为什么不在你寻找一个买家之前 让我看看我能做什么。
A few days wouIdn't make much difference to you, I don't suppose.
我想几天的时间不会对你有太大的区别。
Might mean a Iot more money for aII of us.
可能对我们所有人来说，意味着更多的钱。
Good. There's just one thing. I disIike to mention it, but...
好。只有一件事。 我不喜欢提起它，但...
-...I've just come from prison and.... -WeII, of course.
-...我刚从监狱出来.... -哦，当然。
Cobby wiII be gIad to advance you anything you need.
考比很高兴给你提供一切你想要的。
-See that you have a pIace to stay. Cobby? -WeII, you bet your Iife.
-你有一个地方可以住吗，考比? -哦，当然。
And I got some fancy phone numbers for you too, Doc.
我还给你准备了一些很好的电话号码，博士。
What's it Iike, a man of your taste, seven years behind the waIIs?
象你这样的人在监狱里七年是怎么度过的呢？
Not too bad.
还不错。
It's a matter of temperament.
这与人的性格有关。
I cause no troubIe. The prison authorities appreciate that.
我不惹麻烦。 狱方喜欢这样。
They made me assistant Iibrarian.
他们给了我一份助理图书馆员的差事。
I'm afraid I wouIdn't make a modeI prisoner.
我恐怕当不了模范犯人。
After this job, it's Mexico for me. I'II Iive Iike a king.
这件事干完后，我要去墨西哥。 象国王一样生活。
Mexican girIs are very pretty.
墨西哥女孩非常漂亮。
I'II have nothing to do aII day Iong but chase them in the sunshine.
我会整天什么也不干， 只是在阳光下追她们。
-You've been very kind, sir. -Good night. Good night.
-你真是太好了，先生。 -晚安。晚安
-Mr. Emmerich. -Cobby.
-艾默瑞先生。 -考比.
What's the big idea, standing there staring at me, UncIe Lon?
站在那里盯着我看是什么意思，伦大叔？
Don't caII me ''UncIe Lon.''
别叫我“伦大叔”。
I thought you Iiked it.
我以为你喜欢这样。
Maybe I did.
可能我过去喜欢。
I don't anymore.
但我现在再也不喜欢了。
I had the market send over some saIt mackereI for you.
我让市场的人给你送了点咸鲭鱼过来。
I know how you Iove it for breakfast.
我知道你喜欢在早餐时吃。
Some sweet kid.
可爱的孩子。
It's Iate.
很晚了。
Why don't you go to bed.
你为什么不上床？
Some sweet kid.
可爱的孩子。
HeIIo, Bob Brannom?
喂，鲍勃・勃兰诺？
This is Emmerich.
我是艾默瑞。
No, no. I didn't caII you to get the right time.
不，不。我打电话有点不是时候。
Listen, I've got a job for you.
听着，我有件事情要你办。
No, no. Nothing Iike that.
不，不。不是那样的事情。
I've got over $ 1 00,000 standing out on my books.
我的帐上有100,000多美元没有收回。
Come to my office tomorrow, I'II give you a Iist of the peopIe that owe me.
明天来我的办公室，我给你一张 欠我的人的名单。
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
Use the method caIIed for in each particuIar case...
在每件特定的案子中使用那种方法...
...and don't teII me anything about it. AII I want is resuIts.
...别跟我说任何事情。 我只想知道结果。
Easy, boy.
放松，孩子。
Easy, boy. Easy.
放松，孩子。放松。
HeIIo. Who?
喂。谁？
Oh, sure, Gus.
哦，当然，戈斯。
He's stiII asIeep.
他还在睡觉。
What?
什么？
Yeah. Yeah, I'II teII him.
是的。是，我会告诉他。
Honey. Honey, that was Gus.
亲爱的。亲爱的，是戈斯打来的。
He says you can come over. He's got something for you.
他说你可以过来。 他有点东西要给你。
Okay.
好吧。
Coffee, honey? I made fresh.
咖啡，亲爱的？我新煮的。
Yeah, yeah.
好的，好的。
Hey, you sure were dreaming.
嘿，你一定是做梦了。
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
You were taIking in your sIeep.
你说梦话了。
What was I saying?
我说什么了？
It was aII jumbIed up, but I heard one word reaI pIain.
大部分都是模糊的， 但我听到一个词很清楚。
You caIIed it out severaI times.
你说了好几遍。
''Corn cracker.''
“爆米花。”
What's that mean?
那是什么意思？
Corn cracker.
爆米花。
Corn Cracker was a coIt.
爆米花是一匹小马。
Yeah, it wouId be.
是的，应该是。
Yeah. He was a taII, bIack coIt. Yeah, I remember what I was dreaming.
是的，它是一匹高个的黑马。 是的，我想起来我梦见什么了。
I was up on that coIt's back.
我骑在那匹马的背上。
My father and my grandfather were there, watching the fun.
我父亲和祖父在那里， 看我的笑话。
That coIt was buckjumping and pitching...
那匹马又踢又咬...
...and tried to scrape me off against the fence, but I stayed with him.
...还想把我从栏杆上蹭下来，但我死死抱着它。
Then I heard my granddaddy say, ''He's a reaI HandIey, that boy. A reaI HandIey.''
然后我听到我爷爷说：“他是一个真正的汉德莱 家的人，那男孩。一个真正汉德莱家的人。”
And I feIt proud as you pIease.
我感到非常自豪。
Did that reaIIy happen, Dix, when you were a kid?
那真的发生过吗，迪克斯， 当你还是一个孩子的时候？
No. The bIack coIt pitched me into a fence on the first buck...
不。那黑马一跳就把我摔到栏杆上了...
...and my oId man come over, prodded me with his boot, said:
...我爸爸走过来， 用他的靴踢了踢我，说：
''Maybe that'II teach you not to brag about how good you are on a horse.''
“也许我应该教教你不要吹牛你骑马有多好。”
It's nice to hear you Iaugh.
你笑起来很好看。
You know something?
你知道吗？
One of my ancestors imported the first Irish thoroughbred into our county.
我的一个祖先引进了这个国家 最早的一匹爱尔兰纯种马。
-Is that a fact? -Sure.
-那是真的吗？ -当然。
Why, our farm was in the famiIy for generations.
为什么，我们的农场已经 延续了好几代人了。
One hundred sixty acres, 30 in bIuegrass and the rest in crops.
一百六十英亩， 30亩蓝草，其余的是庄稼。
Fine barn and seven brood mares.
一个很好的谷仓和七个马棚。
-It sounds wonderfuI, Dix. -It was.
-听起来很不错，迪克斯。 -是的。
And then everything happened at once.
后来事情急转直下。
My oId man died, and we Iost our corn crop.
我父亲去世了， 我们失去了所有的庄稼。
That bIack coIt I was teIIing you about, he broke his Ieg and had to be shot.
我跟你说过的那匹黑马， 它的腿断了，不得不杀死它。
That was a rotten year.
那真是倒霉的一年。
I'II never forget the day we Ieft.
我永远忘不了我们离开的那天。
Me and my brother swore we'd buy Hickorywood Farm back someday.
我和我的哥哥发誓总有一天要 把希刻伍德农场再买回来。
Growing up in a pIace and then having to Ieave must be awfuI.
在一个地方长大，然后被迫离开 一定很可怕。
I never had a proper home.
我从来没有一个固定的家。
TweIve grand wouId have swung it, and I aImost made it once.
一万二就能有一个， 我几乎快要实现了。
I had more than $5000 in my pocket...
我兜里有5000多美元...
...and Pampoon was running in the Suburban.
...蓬蓬要在郊区赛马场跑。
I figured he couIdn't Iose. I put it aII on his nose.
我认为它不可能输。 我把所有的钱都赌在它身上。
He Iost by a nose.
结果它还是输了。
Drink your coffee, honey, before it gets coId.
亲爱的，喝你的咖啡， 快要凉了。
The way I figure, my Iuck's just gotta turn.
我认为， 我快要时来运转了。
One of these days, I'II make a reaI kiIIing, then I'm gonna head for home.
这几天，我就要大干一场， 然后我就回家。
First thing I do, I take a bath in the creek and get this city dirt off me.
回家做的第一件事就是在小河里洗个澡 把这个城市的尘土全洗掉。
-What's the matter? -Nothing, Dix. Nothing.
-怎么了？ -没什么，迪克斯。没什么。
-I say something wrong? -No.
-我说错什么了？ -没有。
But, gee, this pIace is a mess. It needs a good cIeaning.
但是，gee, 这地方一团糟。 需要好好打扫了。
How can you stand to Iive Iike this?
你怎么能这样生活？
Count it.
数一数。
-Count it. -Don't have to pay the whoIe tab at once.
-数一数。 -不用马上就还清所有的帐单。
Go ahead and count it.
继续数。
Why get sore? There's no reason to get sore.
为什么生气？ 没有理由生气。
You boned me in front of a stranger, made me Iook smaII.
你在一个陌生人面前挑我的刺， 让我很丢面子。
I didn't mean it. I shoot my mouth off.
我不想那样。 我马上就闭嘴了。
Maybe I had a sIight Ioad on. You know how it is.
可能我有点负担。 你知道那是怎么回事。
No, I don't know how it is.
不，我不知道那是怎么回事。
Look, Dix...
听着，迪克斯...
...I made a mistake.
...我犯了一个错误。
Don't you ever make a mistake? Sure.
你从来不犯错误吗？当然。
Sure. Here, have a drink.
当然。给你，喝点吧。
Here you are.
给你。
There you are, Dix.
给你，迪克斯。
You gotta pIay the horses the smart way. Save your money.
你最好赌马的时候聪明点。 省点钱。
The next time there's a fix, I'II Iet you know. It'II be money from home.
下次有机会，我会让你知道的。 很容易赚的。
Excuse me.
对不起。
Oh, it's the Doc. Come on in, Doc.
哦，是博士。请进，博士。
Meet a friend of mine, Dix HandIey.
见见我的一个朋友，迪克斯・汉德莱。
This is Doc Riedenschneider. You heard of him, I guess.
这是林登施耐德博士。 我想你听说过他。
Yeah.
是的。
WeII, how'd you Iike the whiskey? Made in your home state.
好，你觉得这威士忌怎么样？ 是你的家乡酿造的。
Where is that, sir?
是哪里，先生？
Kentucky. Boone County, Kentucky.
肯塔基。波恩郡，肯塔基州。
-Best water in the U.S.A. -Is that so?
-全美国最好的水。 -是吗？
Yes, the water makes the whiskey fit to drink.
是的，水使威士忌好喝。
WeII...
好...
...I gotta be going. I'II see you around, maybe.
...我要走了。 我可能会再见你。
So Iong, Dix.
再见，迪克斯.
Big hick.
乡巴佬。
His money's aII right, but I wish he wasn't so touchy.
他还的钱没问题， 但我希望他不是那么敏感。
Maybe it's a point of honor with him. A gambIing debt.
可能那是他的一种荣誉。 一些赌债。
Him, that hooIigan? Honor? Don't make me Iaugh.
他，那个流氓？荣誉？ 别逗了。
-He's a hooIigan? -Yeah, but a smaIItimer.
-他是一个流氓？ -是的，只是一个小流氓。
He'II stick up cigar stores, gas stations. And every cent goes to the ponies.
他抢劫杂货店，加油站。 把所有钱都拿走，连硬币也不放过。
One way or another, we aII work for our vice.
在某种程度上来说， 我们都在为我们的罪恶打工。
What do you say, Doc? How was your date Iast night?
你说什么，博士？ 你昨天晚上的约会怎么样？
The young Iady drank too much, but the evening wasn't a compIete Ioss.
那位年轻的女士喝太多了， 但是时间并没有完全浪费。
-She taIked more than if she'd been sober. -Yeah? What about?
-她说了很多清醒时不会说的话。 -是吗？关于什么？
-Your friend Mr. Emmerich. -Emmerich? Now, Iook here, Doc--
-你的朋友艾默瑞先生。 -艾默瑞？好，听我说，博士--
There's haIf a miIIion at stake. I've gotta know where I stand.
这次行动有五十万。 我必须知道我的立场。
Emmerich must put up before I can hire a crew.
艾默瑞必须在我雇人之钱提供钱。
For him, it's nothing. A dead cinch.
对他来说，那不算什么。一点小意思。
The information she gave me is that he's broke.
她给我的情报是他快要破产了。
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗？
I've seen him operate for 20 years. He handIes onIy the biggest cases.
我看着他操作了20年。 他处理的都是大买卖。
He's got two houses, four cars, haIf a dozen servants--
他有两套房子，四部汽车，六个佣人--
-And one bIond. -Doc, whose word you gonna take?
-其中一个还是白人。 -博士，你愿意相信谁的话？
Mine or some dimwitted dame?
我的还是一个不可靠的女人的？
Yours, naturaIIy.
当然是你的。
If he's broke, I wanna be broke the same way.
如果他破产了，我宁愿象他一样破产。
Lieutenant! Lieutenant!
中尉！中尉！
That guy you saw in my office, he's just passing through.
你在我办公室看见的那个， 他只是路过。
Shut up. I didn't see anybody. How couId I? I wasn't here.
闭嘴。我没看见任何人。 我怎么会看见？我又没来过这里。
Yeah, that's right. That's right.
是的，没错。没错。
-Look.... -Yeah?
-听着.... -什么？
I came to teII you you'II have to stand stiII for a raid.
我来告诉你 你必须停下来等待搜查。
-You mean they'II hauI me downtown? -It's a short ride.
-你是说他们要把我带到市区？ -只是很短的路。
I thought you were a friend of mine.
我以为你是我的一个朋友。
Right now I've got one friend: Ditrich.
现在我有一个朋友了：迪特里奇。
And Ditrich's out on his ear if he don't make a showing.
如果他不愿意出面， 迪特里奇就听不见。
-Why me? Why pick on me? -Because it's Iogic.
-为什么是我？为什么要选我？ -因为是合情合理的。
You're the biggest parIor in my precinct.
你是我管区里最大的庄家。
The citizens know it, the newspapers know it and even I know it.
市民们知道，报纸知道，甚至连我都知道。
-And Mr. Commissioner knows I know it. -I just hate to have it happen, that's aII.
-而且专员先生知道我知道。 -我就是讨厌这种事情发生，就这样。
-I'm as sorry as you are. -Look, Iieutenant...
-我也很抱歉。 -听着，中尉...
...I've aIways given you pIenty of cooperation...
...我总是给你充分的合作...
...but you're hitting me at just the wrong time.
...但你现在找我找的不是时候。
WeII, aII right.
哦，好吧。
CIose up tight.
把门关紧点。
Keep the pIace dark. Don't answer any phones.
别开灯，保持黑暗。 别接任何电话。
Thanks, Iieutenant.
谢谢，中尉.
Thanks.
谢谢。
That copper, he recognized me.
那个警察，他认出我来了。
-How'd you know he was a copper? -I can smeII one a bIock off.
-你怎么知道他是警察？ -我在一里地以外就能闻出来。
Don't worry about Ditrich. He's on my payroII.
别担心迪特里奇。 我付钱给他。
Me and him, we're Iike that.
我和他，我们就象这样。
Experience taught me never to trust a poIiceman.
经验告诉我，永远不要相信一个警察。
Just when you think one's aII right, he turns Iegit.
当你以为他没问题的时候， 他就变了。
-A Mr. Brannom is here. -Oh, yes, show him in.
-有一个勃兰诺先生在这里。 -哦，是的，让他进来。
Pardon me, sir. Mrs. Emmerich is not feeIing weII.
对不起，先生。 艾默瑞夫人有点不舒服。
Yes, weII...
是，好吧...
-...send for Dr. Houseman. -I aIready have, sir.
-...送她去见豪斯曼医生。 -我已经做了，先生。
Good.
好。
TeII her....
告诉她....
Say I'II be up to see her Iater.
说我迟点去见她。
WeII, what about my debtors? How many of them came through?
好，那些欠我钱的人怎么样了？ 他们还了多少？
-Not a one. -What's that?
-一个也没有。 -你说什么？
You want aII the excuses?
你想听所有那些借口吗？
-I've got some beauts. -It's as bad as that, eh?
-有些很美妙。 -很糟糕，是吗？
Two or three may come through with a part.
有两三个人可能愿意还一部分。
-They promised. -I don't want promises, I want cash.
-他们许诺了。 -我不要许诺，我要现金。
Look, my friend, a private detective can't go around threatening peopIe.
听着，朋友，一个私人侦探 不能走来走去威胁别人。
I'd Iose my Iicense. Ninety-eight percent of them you're gonna have to sue.
我丢了我的执照。98%的可能你必须起诉他们。
There's no time for that.
没时间做那个。
I gotta have money. I've gotta have it this minute.
我必须拿到钱。 我必须立刻拿到钱。
What is it, girI troubIe?
是什么问题，女人的麻烦？
Shut up, Brannom! That's not funny.
闭嘴，勃兰诺！那不好玩。
How's that? Nobody teIIs me to shut up.
怎么了？ 没有人敢让我闭嘴。
Sorry, Bob.
对不起，鲍勃。
Bob, I--
鲍勃，我--
I'm broke.
我破产了。
There. That's the pIain, simpIe fact.
事实就是这么简单。
I'm finished. I'm bankrupt.
我完蛋了。我破产了。
-How couId you Iet AngeIa take you? -It's not AngeIa.
-你怎么能让安吉拉把你弄成这样？ -不是安吉拉。
It's everything. It's my whoIe way of Iife.
是所有的事情。是我的生活方式。
Every time I turn around, it costs thousands of doIIars. 1 0,000 here, 1 0,000 there.
每次我一转身，就会花掉上万的钱。 这儿一万，那儿一万。
I gotta-- I gotta get out.
我必须--我必须扭转。
I gotta get out from under.
我必须扭转这种局面。
And the irony of it is that I've got an opportunity...
最讽刺的是我已经有机会了...
-...and I can't take it. -Tough.
-...但我却不能抓住。 -唉。
Bob...
鲍勃...
...I'm gonna hand you the shock of a Iifetime.
...我有一个惊人的计划要告诉你。
Did you ever hear of Doc Riedenschneider?
你听说过林登施耐德博士吗？
Sure. Behind the waIIs, isn't he?
当然。他被抓起来了，对吗？
No, he's out. He got out Iast week. Cobby brought him to me.
不，他出来了。上周出来的。 考比带他来见我了
He's got a pIan, beautifuIIy worked out...
他有一个计划，完美的计划...
...for the biggest caper ever to be puIIed in the MiddIe West.
...中西部地区有史以来最大的案子。
OnIy, he wants $50,000 backing.
只是，他想要50,000美元。
Who wouId be taken?
他准备偷谁？
BeIIetier's.
贝利蒂。
The rocks aIone wouId be worth, conservativeIy speaking, haIf a miIIion.
光宝石就值， 保守地说，五十万。
-How much wouId you get out of it? -A third of the take.
-你能从中得到多少？ -三分之一。
Brother. You're knocking me out.
兄弟。你吓着我了。
What if I were to teII you that I've got a pIan worked out to get it aII?
如果我跟你说我有一个计划 可以独吞所有的，你觉得如何？
I couId teII them that I'd fence the stuff myseIf, you see?
我可以告诉他们说 我自己来当买家，你明白？
Promise them cash on deIivery.
许诺他们现金正在路上。
Then...
然后...
...when the time comes, I simpIy wouIdn't have the cash.
...时间到了， 我没有那么多钱。
I'd teII them it'd take a few days more to raise it.
我会告诉他们还需要几天时间 来准备那么多钱。
I'm certain I couId get them to Ieave the stuff with me whiIe we're waiting.
我肯定可以让他们在我们 等待的时候把东西留在我这儿。
-Go on. -WeII, then I'd disappear.
-往下说。 -好，然后我就消失了。
I'd take a pIane to another country, to another Iife.
我要坐飞机去另一个国家，开始新生活。
The goId and pIatinum I couId meIt up and seII as buIIion, you see.
黄金和白金我可以把 它们熔化成块卖掉，你知道。
And the rocks, seII them one at a time.
至于那些宝石，每次卖一颗。
There'd be no hurry.
没必要着急。
They'd Iast a Iifetime.
一生也用不完。
How wrong can a guy be?
一个人可以错到什么程度啊？
Here I was worrying about your nerves...
我有点担心你的神经...
...and you were dreaming up a doubIe-cross Iike this.
...你在梦想双重欺诈。
Yes.
是的。
But I can't do it, because I haven't got $50,000.
但我不能那么做，因为我还 没有拿到50,000美元。
I can teII you how to raise it.
我可以告诉你怎么拿到那些钱。
You? How?
你？怎么多拿？
-What's in it for me? -Fifty-fifty.
-我能有什么好处？ -五五分成。
Okay.
好吧。
But we may get ourseIves kiIIed, my friend.
但我们会被人干掉的，朋友。
Yes, I know.
是的，我知道。
-WeII, how do we raise the money? -SimpIe. Cobby.
-好吧，我们怎么多拿钱？ -简单。通过考比。
-Cobby. -BeIieve me.
-考比？ -相信我。
He can dig it up without haIf-trying.
他手里的钱足够。
Yes.
是的。
But what do we teII him? Why do I need money?
但我们告诉他什么？ 我为什么会需要钱？
Leave it to me. Cobby wants to feeI big.
让我来做。考比总想干大事。
Here's his chance.
给他一个机会。
Advancing money for the great AIonzo P. Emmerich.
借钱给伟大的阿伦佐・皮・艾默瑞。
He'II do it.
他会很乐意去做。
He'II sweat, but he'II do it.
他会流汗，但他会去做。
What boxes have you opened?
你曾经开过什么样的保险柜？
CannonbaII, doubIe door, even a few fire chests. AII of them.
炮弹型，双层门， 甚至一些火箱。各种各样的。
-Can you open a vauIt with a time Iock? -Sure.
-你能打开带时间锁的柜子吗？ -当然。
-What do you use, Iock or seam? -Seam.
-你从哪里入手，锁还是接缝？ -接缝。
Ever taken one?
曾经做过吗？
-Remember the Shafter job? -Yes, I heard about it behind the waIIs.
-知道夏弗特案吗？ -是的，我在狱里的时候听说过。
It was a good score.
干得很漂亮。
-Who suppIies your soup? -I thrash it myseIf.
-谁提供你炸药？ -我自己制造。
-How are you as a pickIock? -I can open anything in four minutes.
-你开锁的技术怎么样？ -我可以四分钟之内打开任何东西。
-He'II do. -You're in.
-他可以来。 -你被录取了。
Not so fast. What's the cut?
别那么快。怎么提成？
No cut. You get a fIat guarantee.
没有提成。你拿死工资。
-I want 30,000. -30,000? Now, Louis....
-我想要30,000。 -30,000？听着，路易斯....
Twenty-five is what we figured.
最多两万五。
-AII right, 1 5 down. -Ten down.
-好吧，不过一万五要先付。 -先付一万。
Fifteen is satisfactory, I think.
我想一万五可以接受。
There's your paymaster.
那是你的付款人。
What are you sweating for?
你为什么要流汗？
Money makes me sweat, that's aII. It's the way I am.
钱总是让我流汗。 我总是这样。
-Who are the others on this job, Doc? -Haven't got them yet.
-还有谁做这件事，博士？ -还没有找到。
There's onIy one driver, as far as I'm concerned. Gus Minissi.
我的熟人里只有一个司机。戈斯・米尼斯。
Ask Cobby, he knows him.
问问考比，他认识他。
-Gus, 1 00 percent. -Get hoId of him.
-戈斯，100%可以。 -录用他。
-He'II take the heat and won't fIap his Iip. -Get hoId of him.
-他打死也不会说的。 -录用他。
Sure, Doc.
当然，博士。
Any ideas about a hooIigan?
有什么合适的流氓吗？
I know a very good heavy. I haven't seen him in some time. Red Traynor.
我认识一个非常棒的。我有段时间 没见到他。雷德・特雷诺。
-He's taking the cure. -RuIe him out.
-他在接受治疗。 -不要他。
What about Timmons?
提蒙斯怎么样？
-Who's that? -My doorman.
-那是谁？ -我的看门人。
That busted-down wrestIer, are you kidding?
那个失败的摔跤手， 你在开玩笑吧？
He's got nothing upstairs but soIid knuckIe.
他除了坚实的关节以外没有任何头脑。
I'm a stranger and do not know as much as you gentIemen...
我是一个外人，不象你们了解的那么多...
...but what about this southerner, this Dix?
...但这个南方人怎么样，这个迪克斯?
He impressed me as a very determined man and far from stupid.
他给我的印象很深，是一个很坚定的人， 而且不愚蠢。
FrankIy, I don't Iike the guy, but I never saw a hooIigan I did Iike.
坦率地说，我不喜欢这家伙， 可我也从没见过一个我喜欢的流氓。
They're Iike Ieft-handed pitchers. They aII have a screw Ioose somewhere.
他们就象左手投手一样。 总是把螺丝弄丢。
I suppose he's as good as anybody, though.
但我认为他和别人一样好。
Gus thinks he's tops, and Gus is usuaIIy right.
戈斯认为他是顶尖的， 而戈斯经常是对的。
I Iike him. I say we take him.
我喜欢他。我的意思是说我们收他。
Suits me. You're the boss.
我没意见。你是老板。
WeII, I better be getting home now. Mrs. CiaveIIi's worried about the kid.
好吧，我最好现在回家。 察维利夫人有点担心孩子。
-What's the troubIe? -He's got a coId again.
-怎么了？ -他又感冒了。
She takes him out first thing in the morning. It's coId then.
她早晨的第一件事就是把他带出去。 那时候很冷。
She cIaims a baby's gotta taste fresh air.
她说孩子应该呼吸新鲜空气。
Like I'm aIways teIIing her, ''If you want fresh air, don't Iook for it in this town!''
我总跟她说：“如果你想要新鲜空气， 这个城市里是没有的！”
Here.
你看。
He's 9 months oId there.
这是他九个月大的时候。
I must say, I envy you, being a famiIy man.
我必须说，作为家庭成员，我都嫉妒他，
Yeah.
是的。
WeII, aIways probIems, huh?
好，总是有很多麻烦，呃？
One good thing about Dix, you can get him for nickeIs and dimes.
迪克斯的一点好处是， 你可以花很少一点钱雇他。
TeII me something, Cobby.
告诉我，考比。
It's your money, isn't it? Not Mr. Emmerich's.
那是你的钱，对吗？ 不是艾默瑞先生的。
-What difference does it make? -None, reaIIy.
-那有什么区别吗？ -没有，真的。
It's this way. Mr. Emmerich doesn't want this transaction appearing in his books.
是这样的。艾默瑞先生不想让 这笔交易出现在他的帐上。
I'm not risking anything. He's good for it in case of a runout.
我没有承担任何风险。 他想很容易脱身。
Then you haven't got a worry.
所以你不必担心。
No.
是的。
-Where are you going? -I found a pIace.
-你要去哪里？ -我找到一个地方。
A girIfriend's Ieaving town. She Iet me have her apartment.
一个女朋友要离开本市。 她让我住她的公寓。
The rent's paid up tiII the first of the month.
这个月的房租已经付了。
-When did this happen? -This morning, before you woke up.
-什么时候发生的？ -今天早晨，在你醒之前。
I bumped into her on the street.
我在街上遇见了她。
Remember that taII brunette, used to do the noveIty dances at the Bandwagon?
还记得那个高个人有点黑的女孩吗， 曾经在班达根跳新舞的？
BIanche LaRue. It sure was nice of her.
勃兰奇・兰瑞。她是一个好人。
I can't go Iiving off you forever, can I?
我不能永远和你住一起，对吗？
-I was gIad to heIp out. -Yeah.
-我很高兴能帮你。 -是的。
WeII, maybe I can do something for you sometime.
好吧，也许我以后能帮你做点什么。
You don't owe me a thing. Forget it.
你不欠我任何东西。没事。
WeII....
好吧....
Goodbye.
再见。
-How are you fixed for dough? -A coupIe of bucks. Enough.
-你还有多少钱？ -几块钱。足够了。
Here, take this and--
给你，拿着这个--
No. No, thanks, Dix.
不。不，谢谢，迪克斯。
I'm aII through bothering.
我已经给你太多麻烦了。
Give us a kiss, huh?
给我一个吻吧，嗯？
DoII.
朵尔。
Yes, Dix?
是的，迪克斯？
Maybe I'II wanna get in touch with you.
可能我还想和你保持联系。
Sure, my new address.
当然，这是我的新地址。
I'II be at 42 Merton Street.
我会住在莫顿街42号。
42 Merton.
莫顿街42号。
-HeIIo. -Hello, Dix?
-喂。 -喂，迪克斯？
-Yeah. -Dix, this is Cobby.
-谁？ -迪克斯，我是考比。
-Oh, hiya, Cobby. -I got your number from Gus.
-哦，你好，考比。 -我从戈斯那儿得到你的电话号码的。
-Yeah. -Look, Dix...
-哦。 -听着，迪克斯...
...do you want to get into something big? I mean, real big.
...你想参加一件大事吗？ 我是说，非常大的事。
If you do, be at Gus' tonight at 1 0:00.
如果你愿意，今天晚上10:00来戈斯家。
Right.
好吧。
Everything's here.
所有东西都在这里了。
The soft spot's an oId steam tunneI. ManhoIe's on the corner.
弱点是一个老的蒸汽管道。 街角上有一个井盖。
You drop into the manhoIe at 1 1 :45. Dix wiII cover you.
你在11:45时跳进井盖。 迪克斯会掩护你。
You break through the waII.
你穿过那堵墙。
It'II take about six minutes to get into BeIIetier's from the furnace room.
大概要花六分钟的时候从锅炉房进到 贝利蒂的房间。
Watch out for fIoor wires.
小心地上的电线。
Make your way up the back stairs and jump the aIarm system.
设法从后面的楼梯上去， 跳开警报系统。
That wiII take another three minutes.
那会花三花钟。
At exactIy 1 1 :54, Dix and I wiII come to the back door.
11:54准时，迪克斯和我会来到后门。
You open it for us.
你为我们打开它。
-I'II be waiting for you. -Good.
-我会在那里等你们。 -好。
Any questions?
有什么问题吗？
-Everything sounds okay. -Same here.
-一切都好。 -我也一样。
WeII, guess I better be getting home.
好，我想我该回家了。
-How's the boy? -Oh, he's okay.
-孩子怎么样？ -哦，他好了。
Ran a temperature yesterday. Pretty high too.
昨天发烧了。 温度很高。
We caIIed the doctor, but temperatures don't mean so much with kids.
我们叫了医生，但对孩子来说发烧不算什么。
He's back to normaI today.
他今天已经恢复正常了。
-See you tomorrow night, 1 1 :30. -Good night.
-明天晚上见，11:30。 -晚安。
Have you got a minute, Dix?
你有时间吗，迪克斯？
Sure. What's on your mind?
当然。你在想什么？
My friend, what do you know about this feIIow Emmerich?
朋友，你对艾默瑞了解多少？
You mean the big fixer? I've heard his name, that's aII.
你是说那个大人物？ 我听说过他的名字，就这些。
-I can taIk to you, I think. -Sure.
-我可以和你说话吗？ -当然。
Mr. Emmerich is taking the jeweIry off our hands.
艾默瑞先生会把 珠宝从我们手中拿走。
You sure are surprising me, Doc.
博士，你真令我吃惊。
I don't exactIy trust Mr. Emmerich.
我不完全相信艾默瑞先生。
Just a feeIing. I may be wrong.
只是一种感觉。可能我是错的。
But it's up to us to coIIect, you and me.
但最后是由我们来收帐，你和我。
Everything may go smooth, but if it don't....
一切都会顺利， 但如果不....
-If he's got it, we'II coIIect. -Good.
-如果他拿到了，我们就收帐。 -好。
We'II meet Mr. Emmerich after the caper, deIiver the jeweIry and get our money.
我们会在得手之后见艾默瑞先生， 拿去珠宝，拿到我们的钱。
The payment is to be immediate and in cash.
付款必须是现付，而且要现金。
After that, we pay off and scatter.
拿到之后，我们付工资然后散伙。
Don't worry, Doc. We'II coIIect.
别担心，博士。我们会拿到的。
Lon...
伦...
...is that you?
...是你吗？
-Lon? -Yes, May.
-伦? -是的，梅。
Come in, Lon.
进来，伦。
-I've got a business appointment. -Sit down a minute.
-我有一个生意上的约会。 -坐一会儿。
It's 1 1 :30. Isn't that rather Iate for business?
已经11:30了，谈生意是不是太晚了？
-Lon. -Yes, May?
-伦。 -是的，梅？
I'm not feeIing weII.
我感觉不太舒服。
You haven't been feeIing weII for a Iong time.
你已经不舒服很长时间了。
At night, I get nervous.
一到晚上，我就神经紧张。
And when I get nervous, I hate to stay in this big house aII by myseIf.
而一旦我紧张，我就讨厌 独自一个呆在这大房子里。
Look here. May, you're not aIone. There are three servants in the house.
看看这里。梅，你不是独自一个。 屋里有三个仆人。
-AII you have to-- -I know. Press a button.
-你需要做的只是-- -我知道。按一下按钮。
WeII, what do you want me to do?
好吧，你想要我做什么？
Sit down, Lon.
坐下，伦.
AII right.
好吧。
Do I sit here and watch you read a magazine?
我就坐在这里看你读杂志？
-WouId that be so awfuI? -Oh, now, Iook, May--
-那很可怕吗？ -好吧，现在，看，梅--
We couId pIay cards.
我们可以玩牌。
-Casino, Iike we used to. -Some other night.
-赌博，就象我们曾经玩过的一样。 -改天吧。
PIease, Lon, just one hand.
来吧，伦，只玩一盘。
I couIdn't sIeep Iast night.
我昨天晚上睡不着。
Then I got to thinking of the oId days...
然后我回想了以前的日子...
...how we used to Iike to stay up and pIay casino. Just the two of us.
...我们多么喜欢呆在一起玩牌。 只有我们两个。
Yes. I wish I couId stay, but I can't.
是的。我也希望我能留下来，但可惜不行。
My dear, this is business.
亲爱的，这是生意。
I teII you what I'II do.
我告诉你我要做什么。
I'II Iook in Iater, and if you're stiII awake, we'II have a IittIe game.
我会晚点回来，如果你还醒着， 我们就小玩一会。
Take your keys, pIease. We're cIosing up.
请带上你的钥匙。我们要关门了。
Okay.
好吧。
-AII set? -Yeah.
-都准备好了？ -是的。
Better be carefuI how you handIe this stuff.
你处理这东西的时候最好小心一点。
They'II pick you up in IittIe pieces.
它们会把你炸成碎片。
What time have you got?
你还有多少时间？
Good.
好。
Good Iuck, Doc.
祝你好运，博士。
Did he give you the soup?
他给你炸药了吗？
Here's the eIectric eye.
这是电子眼监控。
Soup.
炸药。
It's gonna take a Iot to bIow this baby.
炸开这个宝贝需要很多炸药。
Here goes.
要开始了。
-What's that? -Keep going.
-那是什么？ -继续做。
Hey, Doc, aIarms are going off aII over the bIock.
嘿，博士，整个街区的警报都响了。
-The bIast must've shook the whoIe system. -What do we do?
-爆炸一定震动了整个系统。 -我们怎么办？
I wouId hate to Ieave now. We're so cIose.
我可不喜欢现在离开。 我们已经快到手了。
-I'm for finishing what we started. -How about you, Louis?
-我要完全我们已经开始的工作。 -你呢，路易斯?
-It's okay with me. -WiII Gus hoId stiII?
-我没问题。 -戈斯会坚持吗？
Don't worry about Gus.
别为戈斯担心。
What's the matter?
发生什么事了？
The driII broke.
钻头坏了。
We shouId finish before 1 2:1 5, before the watchman gets here.
我们应该在12:15之前完成， 在守卫到这儿之前。
The store cop? Let me worry about him.
店铺警察？让我来对付他。
-Hear that, Dix? -Yeah.
-听到了吗，迪克斯？ -是的。
-Coming this way? -From the river. Don't sound good.
-往这边来了吗？ -从河那边来的。别太大声。
Take a Iook, see what's happening.
去看看发生什么了。
We gotta bIow, fast!
我们必须走了，快！
This is everything of reaI vaIue.
这是真正有价值的东西。
-Heavy, ain't she? -PIenty.
-很重，是吗？ -足够重。
This is the biggest one yet.
这是最大的一桩。
Wait tiII you see it in the papers.
等着看报纸吧。
Watchman. PuII open the door, Louis.
守卫。拉开门，路易斯。
-Maybe he'II go away. -Do what Dix says.
-可能他要离开。 -按迪克斯说的做。
Now.
开！
FoIIow me.
跟我来。
-Gus, take me home. -Where did it get you?
-戈斯，带我回家吧。 -打在你哪儿了？
Thigh. I can feeI it going up. I think I got the sIug in my beIIy.
大腿。我觉得它向上去了。 我想子弹打在我肚子里了。
-I'II take you to a guy, used to be a doctor. -No, no. Take me home, Gus!
-我带你去见一个人，他以前当过医生。 -不，不。带我回家，戈斯!
AII right, Louis.
好吧，路易斯。
It's after 1 . They shouId be here any minute.
已经一点多了。 他们随时会在这儿。
UnIess there's been troubIe.
除非有麻烦。
Where is AngeIa tonight?
今晚安吉拉在哪里？
She's at her sister's.
她在她姐姐家。
She says.
她是那么说。
I'd go easy on that Iiquor if I were you.
如果我是你我会少喝点。
HaIf-drunk, I got better wits than most peopIe.
半醉而已，我比大多数人酒量大。
And more nerve.
也更有头脑。
You Iook worried, my friend.
你看起来很担忧，我的朋友。
Something bothering you?
什么事烦扰你了吗？
Live and Iearn.
活到老，学到老。
AII these years, I've been suffering from an inferiority compIex.
这么多年来，我一直有强烈的自卑感。
I shouId've been in the money years ago.
我早在几年前就应该有钱了。
You big boys, what have you got?
大孩子，你得到了什么？
Front. Nothing but front.
面子。什么也没有，只是面子。
And when that sIips....
而当它倒下的时候....
I do beIieve our guests are arriving.
我相信我们的客人们要到了。
WeII? Everything go aII right?
好？一切顺利？
This is a friend of mine, Mr. Brannom.
这是我的一个朋友，勃兰诺先生。
He's been a great heIp to me on this deaI.
他在这件事情上给过我很大帮助。
FoIIow me. FoIIow me, gentIemen.
跟我来。跟我来，先生们。
It's much more comfortabIe in here.
这里要舒服得多。
Say, I'II bet that thing is fuII of Koh-i-noors and Grand MoguIs, eh?
这么说，我敢打赌那东西一定 盛满了各种各样的宝石，嗯？
CouId be.
应该是。
Sit down, gentIemen. Sit down.
坐下，先生们。坐下。
-Let me get you a drink. -No, thanks.
-让我给你倒杯饮料。 -不，谢谢。
Do you mind if we have a Iook?
你介意我们参观一下吗？
You're entitIed to a Iook, naturaIIy.
你当然有资格看看。
-Convinced? -Why, of course. Of course.
-证实了？ -哦，当然。当然。
There never was any doubt in my mind. You know, I know this feIIow's reputation.
我从来也没有怀疑过。 你知道，我知道这家伙的信誉。
Just a matter of curiosity, that's aII.
只是有一点好奇。就是这样。
I'II bet the appraisaI is going to exceed even your estimate--
我敢打赌估价甚至会超过你预计的--
Good. Good.
好。好。
In that case, I'd just Iike to see the coIor of the money.
目前，我只想看到钱的颜色。
GentIemen, I must admit at this moment I....
先生们，此刻我必须承认我....
I'm embarrassed.
我有点难堪。
-You mean you haven't got the money? -Oh, I have it.
-你是说你没有拿到钱？ -哦，我有。
-That is, I have the assurance of it. -You haven't got it.
-就是说，我有拿到钱的保证。 -你还没有拿到。
No, I haven't got the currency right here in my hands...
是的，我现在手里没有钞票...
...but it's promised by an unimpeachabIe source.
...但有无可怀疑的来源保证。
GentIemen, I'm afraid we were a IittIe hasty. We moved too fast.
先生们，恐怕我们有点太仓促了。 我们行动的太快了。
We moved on your word.
我们是按你的话行动的。
Wait a minute. That's a Iarge sum of money, you know...
等一下。 那可是一大笔钱，你知道...
...considering present-day conditions...
...考虑到近期的情况...
...and considering the fact that we had to have it in cash.
...还有考虑到我们必须 拿到现金的事实。
So I'm afraid a few days more are needed to raise it.
所以我恐怕还需要几天才能 拿到钱。
A few days more may not seem Iike a very Iong time to you, Mr. Emmerich.
几天时间对你来说不算长，艾默瑞先生。
But to me, carrying this around, it wouId seem Iike years.
但对我来说，带着这个四处走， 简直就是度日如年。
I understand. I've got a soIution for that too.
我理解。 我也有一个解决办法。
That is, if you boys trust me.
这样，如果你们相信我。
And if you don't, weII, there's nothing I can say except that I'm sorry.
如果你们不信我的话，好吧， 除了说声抱歉以外我也无话可说。
Mr. Emmerich, what are you trying to teII us?
艾默瑞先生， 你想告诉我们什么？
About the jeweIs.
关于这些珠宝。
WouIdn't be safe for you to carry that stuff around.
你们带着那东西四处走确实不安全。
You mean, we Ieave them with you?
你的意思是说，我们把它留在你这里？
WeII, when the poIice start Iooking for that stuff tomorrow morning...
好，明天早晨当警察们开始寻找 那东西的时候...
...they're not IikeIy to caII me up.
...他们肯定不会来我这里。
They're not IikeIy to send detectives out to search my house, you know.
他们也不会派侦探来搜查我的房子， 你知道。
You, on the other hand, Doc, you....
你，从另外一方面来说，博士，你....
You're just out of prison.
你刚从监狱里出来。
They're certainIy gonna be Iooking for the big-timers Iike yourseIf.
他们肯定会寻找象你这样的要犯。
Some smart cop might even connect this burgIary with your reIease.
一些聪明的警察甚至会把 这件劫案和你联系起来。
WeII, there you are.
好吧，给你。
Of course, as I said, it's up to you.
当然，就象我说的，一切由你决定。
Keep in touch with me through Cobby.
通过考比和我保持联系。
You did a great job, Emmerich, but it's not working.
你做的很不错，艾默瑞， 但并不如你愿。
-Bob! -Back away and keep out of this, Emmerich.
-鲍勃! -退后，离它远点，艾默瑞。
Now, you, farmer, get your hands up.
现在，你，农民，举起手来。
And you, Fritz...
还有你，弗里茨...
...throw the bag on the fIoor.
...把包扔在地板上。
Over here by my feet.
扔到我脚前。
Be carefuI how you throw it.
扔的时候小心点。
I got a pistoI expert medaI.
我有手枪专家奖章。
-What do you say, Dix? -He's got no say.
-你说怎么办，迪克斯？ -他无话可说。
He makes a crooked move, he'II never pitch another forkfuI of manure.
他要敢稍微一动， 他这辈子就别想再拿粪叉了。
He's got us, Doc. Toss him the bag.
他制住我们了，博士。把包扔给他。
You're not as dumb as you Iook.
你不象你看起来的那么傻。
Are you a man or what?
你是男人吗？
Trying to gyp and doubIe-cross me with no guts for it.
想要欺骗和双重欺诈我， 却又没有勇气。
What's inside of you? What's keeping you aIive?
你心里在想什么？ 还活着干什么？
Why don't you kiII me?
你为什么不杀我？
-What's stopping you? -Okay, mister--
-是什么阻止了你？ -好吧，先生--
Dix, Iisten to me. Don't kiII him. It's too easy an out for him.
迪克斯，听我说。别杀他。 那样太便宜他了。
Sit down, sir.
坐下，先生。
Whatever possessed you to puII such a stunt?
是什么使你耍这样的手段？
I was broke, facing bankruptcy.
我破产了，面临银行破产。
He's a witness. He saw me knock off that guy.
他是目击者。 他看见我打倒了那家伙。
-You think he wouIdn't hoIIer? -He's in no position to taIk.
-你认为他不会大声叫喊？ -他的处境无法说话。
What did you and your man on the fIoor intend to do with the jeweIs?
你和那个地板上的你的人 准备拿这些珠宝怎么办？
Leave town. SeII them off a IittIe at a time.
离开城镇。 一次卖一小点。
No good. The poIice wouId have been on you after the first saIe.
不好。警察会在你第一次卖就盯上你。
You can't go peddIing stuff Iike this around when the heat's on.
侦查还在进行的时候， 你不可能沿街叫卖这东西。
Let's not fooI around here any Ionger.
我们别在这里傻呆着了。
Be patient, Dix.
耐心点，迪克斯。
Mr. Emmerich got us into this hoIe, and he's going to get us out.
艾默瑞先生把我们陷进这个洞里， 他也能把我们带出去。
I didn't save your Iife because I'm a Iover of humanity.
我饶你不死并不是因为我喜欢人道主义。
We're in troubIe with this satcheI fuII of jeweIs.
我们带着这装满了珠宝的东西有麻烦。
As things stand, it's just so much junk.
目前情况来说，这只是一堆废物。
-There's nothing I can do. -Yes, there is, Mr. Emmerich.
-我什么也做不了。 -不，你可以做，艾默瑞先生。
You can go to the insurance company.
你可以去保险公司。
-Insurance company? -They'II Iisten to reason.
-保险公司？ -他们会听原因。
This is a very bad joIt for them.
对他们来说，这是一个非常不好的处境。
It's possibIe they'II be wiIIing to buy the jeweIs back, no questions asked...
他们很可能愿意买回这些珠宝， 而不会问任何问题...
...for as high as 25 percent of what they're worth.
...他们最多会愿意付珠宝价值25%的钱。
Doc, Iet's bIow.
博士，我们走吧。
I'II start on it tomorrow.
我明天就开始做这件事。
Get busy, Emmerich.
忙起来吧，艾默瑞。
And remember, you might have been Iying here dead with your friend.
记住，你也可能象你的朋友一样 死在这里。
ShaII I get in touch with you through Cobby?
我能通过考比和你保持联系吗？
No. I'II get in touch with you.
不。我会联系你的。
Come on, Dix.
走吧，迪克斯。
I advise you to cIean up after your friend.
我建议你料理一下你朋友的后事。
-Don't give him any water. -He asked for it.
-别给他任何水。 -他要的。
-I said, don't give him any water. -Let go.
-我说，别给他任何水。 -走吧。
You wanna kiII him? Maybe he's hurt in the stomach.
你想杀了他吗？ 他可能伤在胃部了。
Where's the doctor? Why doesn't he come?
医生在哪里？ 他为什么不来？
You said 1 0 minutes. It's haIf an hour.
你说的10分钟。现在已经半个小时了。
Louis wiII die.
路易斯要死了。
Why can't I take him to the hospitaI?
我为什么不可以送他去医院？
They wheeI him into an operating room, you'II never see him again.
他们会把他推进手术室， 你再也不会见到他了。
Take it easy, Maria. Louis is gonna be aII right.
放松，玛丽亚。 路易斯会没事的。
The doctor wiII be here, fix him up good as new.
医生会来这里， 把他完全治好的。
You and Louis are gonna have six more kids.
你和路易斯会有超过六个孩子。
AII as fat as pigs, big bIack eyes, Iots of hair.
个个都白白胖胖，有黑色的大眼睛， 浓密的头发。
Just Iike Louis, eh, Maria?
就象路易斯一样，嗯，玛丽亚？
Stay away from the baby!
离孩子远点！
TeII me the truth. How did it happen?
告诉我真相。 这是怎么发生的？
-I toId you. A fight. -Louis don't fight. You know that.
-我告诉过你了。一场打架。 -路易斯从不打架。你知道那个。
Why is it aIways you?
为什么总是你？
Whenever Louis gets into troubIe, you're around.
路易斯只要一遇到麻烦，总是你在旁边。
You dirty crippIe! You crooked-back!
肮脏的瘸子！驼子！
-You have the eviI eye! -Shut your mouth, Maria!
-你有魔鬼的眼睛！ -闭上你的嘴，玛丽亚！
I don't Iet anybody say that to me.
我不允许任何人那样对我说话。
I'm sorry, Gus...
对不起，戈斯...
...but I gotta bIame somebody.
...但我必须骂什么人。
What I carry on my back, I was born with it.
我所背负的罪孽， 是生来就有的。
I didn't grow it myseIf.
不是我自己长出来的。
PIease forgive me, Gus. I didn't mean it.
请原谅我，戈斯。我不是那个意思。
-Listen to that. -Yeah. Must be a fire.
-听。 -是的。一定是失火了。
It's not in this neighborhood, though. SomepIace eIse.
但不是这里邻近的地方。 别的什么地方。
Oh, Gus. I pray to God that doctor get here quick.
哦，戈斯。我祈祷 那个医生快点来这里。
He'II be here any minute, Maria.
他马上就来，玛丽亚。
Sounds Iike a souI in heII.
听起来就象是地狱里幽灵的声音。
Dix, why don't you get in touch with Gus and Iet him take you to the doctor.
迪克斯, 你为什么不和戈斯联系一下 让他送你去找医生？
-Don't be fooIish. -I don't Iike doctors.
-别傻了。 -我不喜欢医生。
I'm getting aIong aII right.
我会自己好的。
That buIIet just ripped through my side and went on about its business.
那子弹只是擦过我侧面， 然后飞走了。
-Good thing I jumped. -How can things go so wrong?
-幸亏我跳了一下。 -事情怎么会错成这个样子？
How is it possibIe?
那怎么可能呢？
One man kiIIed, two others pIugged.
一个人死了， 另外两个挨了枪。
I'm out 30 grand. We got a Ioad of rocks we can't even peddIe.
我付出了30000美元。我们得到了 一堆宝石，却不能叫卖。
Quit crying and get me some bourbon.
别叫了，给我拿点酒来。
I must be awfuI stupid.
我一定非常愚蠢。
Here I am with a good business...
这儿我有一个很好的买卖...
...money roIIing in...
...财源滚滚...
...I gotta get mixed up in a thing Iike this.
...我竟然卷进了这样的一件事情里。
I ought to have my head examined.
我真应该去检查检查我的大脑。
Yeah, heIIo, heIIo. Yeah, this is Cobby.
是，喂，喂。 是，我是考比。
What?
什么？
It's Gus. Dragnet's out, and they're combing the district.
这是戈斯。搜查开始了， 他们正在彻底搜查这一地区。
He wants to taIk to you. You, Dix.
他想和你说话。 你，迪克斯。
Gus? Dix.
戈斯?我是迪克斯。
Yeah. Listen carefuI.
是的。仔细听我说。
Cops are knocking over joints aIong the bouIevard, meat wagons and aII.
警察们敲开了马路两边 所有商铺的门，还有食品车和一切。
Now, Iook, I aIready caIIed a guy, Eddie Donato.
现在，听着，我已经给一个人打电话了， 艾迪・多内特。
Donato's got a grocery down by the river. 1 1 6 Front Street. You got that?
多内特在河边有一家杂货铺。 前街116号。记住了吗？
Yeah. Thanks, Gus. How's Louis?
是的。谢谢，戈斯。路易斯怎么样？
Louis is not so good. He got a sIug in his beIIy. Doc's doing aII he can.
路易斯不太好。他肚子里有一颗子弹。 医生正在尽全力。
Here they are now, the happiness boys.
现在他们来了，那些警察。
HeIIo. How are you? Looks Iike I'm in for a working-over.
喂。你好吗？ 看起来我也有事了。
Look. Go down to Eddie's by way of the oId car barn.
听着。去艾迪家， 在旧车库旁边。
It's deserted at night. You get beyond that, you're okay.
晚上那里没人。 离你那里很近，没问题。
Cops never bother Eddie's neighborhood. So Iong, Dix. BIow now.
警察从不打扰艾迪的邻居。 再见，迪克斯。现在走吧。
AII right, aII right, aII right.
来了，来了，来了。
What? PIease taIk a IittIe Iouder.
什么？请大声点说话。
This is Eddie Donato.
我是艾迪・多内特。
Oh, sure, sure. I'II get Doc for you.
哦，当然，当然。 我给你找博士。
Hey, dottore, I got your man.
嘿，博士，是你的人。
HeIIo.
喂。
Yes.
是的。
Fine, fine.
好的，好的。
Good.
好。
That wiII be satisfactory.
很满意。
-Cobby? -Yes.
-考比? -是的。
Emmerich came through.
艾默瑞搞定了。
The insurance peopIe say okay.
保险公司的人说可以。
Of course, we have to wait tiII the banks open Monday morning.
当然，我们必须等到 星期一早上银行开门。
But it's 250,000, which is not bad.
但那是250,000，也不错了。
-What's the matter? -As a Iawyer, you may be very briIIiant.
-怎么了？ -作为一个律师，你可能非常聪明。
But as a casino pIayer, you have a Iot to Iearn.
但作为一个赌徒来说， 你还有很多东西要学。
-You don't mind if I smoke, do you? -Of course not, Lon.
-我抽烟你不介意吧，是吧？ -当然不介意，伦。
Lon, how couId you make a pIay Iike that?
伦，你怎么能这么玩？
You won't make a singIe point this hand.
这手牌你一分也得不到。
-Come in. -Two gentIemen to see you, sir.
-进来。 -有两位先生要见你，先生。
They are from the poIice department.
他们是从警察局来的。
What on earth couId they want, Lon?
他们到底想要什么，伦？
WeII, something to do with a case, I suppose.
哦，我想可能是和某个案子有关事情。
-Excuse me? -Oh, bother. We were having so much fun.
-对不起？ -哦，真麻烦。我们正玩的高兴呢。
-Hurry back. -Sure.
-快点回来。 -当然。
-Yes? -Sorry to disturb you, Mr. Emmerich.
-什么事？ -很抱歉打扰你，艾默瑞先生。
I'm Andrews. This is Officer Janocek.
我是安德鲁。 这位是詹诺赛克警官。
-How do you do? -How are you?
-你好。 -你好。
WeII, what can I do for you?
嗯，我能为你们做什么？
Do you know a man named Robert Brannom?
你认识一个叫罗伯特・勃兰诺的人吗？
Brannom. Yes, of course.
勃兰诺。是的，当然。
What is it? Something the matter?
怎么了？ 发生什么事情了？
There sure is, Mr. Emmerich.
肯定是的，艾默瑞先生。
His body was puIIed out of the river this morning.
今天早晨他的尸体在河里被发现了。
-Great heavens. -But it was no drowning.
-哦，上帝。 -但不是淹死的。
He had a hoIe through his pump.
他胸前有一个洞。
He'd been shot.
他是被开枪打死的。
WiII you step in here for a minute?
你们能进来一下吗？
WeII, I must say, this is....
哦，我不得不说，这真是....
It's quite a shock. Bob Brannom, eh?
这真令人吃惊。 鲍勃 勃兰诺，呃？
Murdered, you say? Great heavens.
你是说，谋杀？ 上帝。
We found a Iist of names in his pocket written on your business stationery.
我们在他的口袋里发现了一张人名单 写在你的商业信笺上。
-Who are these peopIe, do you know? -Oh, that's a Iist of my debtors.
-这些人是谁，你知道吗？ -哦，那是一张我的债务人的列表。
Brannom was working for me. He was trying to coIIect oId debts...
勃兰诺为我工作。 他正忙着讨那些旧债...
...without much success, I must say.
...不太成功，我不得不说。
Was he giving the treatment to anybody on this Iist?
他曾经跟这名单上的 什么人有过接触吗？
CertainIy not.
当然没有。
Then you don't think there's any connection between this work for you and his death?
那么你认为为你工作这件事情和 他的死之间没有任何关系？
-None whatever. -When did you see him Iast?
-一点也没有。 -你最后一次见他是什么时候？
WeII, now, Iast Wednesday evening, in this room.
哦，这样，上周三晚上。 就在这间屋子里。
Yes. We went over that Iist together.
是的。我们一起看了那张单子。
The coroner says he was pIugged at 1 :00 or 2:00 this morning.
验尸官说他是今天早上 1:00或者2:00被打死的。
Not much after the BeIIetier job was puIIed.
比贝利蒂被劫案稍晚一点。
We figured there might be a connection.
我们认为这之间可能有联系。
One of the heist guys was shot, we know that.
我们知道有一个劫匪被击中了。
There was bIood on the fIoor. Maybe it was Brannom's.
地板上有血迹。 可能那是勃兰诺的。
He couId've died in the car, they dropped him in the river.
他可能死在汽车里， 他们把他扔到了河里。
Oh, no, no. Bob Brannom's a good deaI of a roughneck, but he's no criminaI.
哦，不，不。鲍勃 勃兰诺有 一点粗暴，但他不是罪犯。
And if I'm any judge, BeIIetier's was the work of bigtime professionaIs.
如果我可以判断的话，贝利蒂案 是很专业的罪犯才能做的。
Oh, no, no, gentIemen. Bob Brannom mixed up in any burgIary...
哦，不，不，先生们。 鲍勃 勃兰诺牵涉到抢劫案中...
...why, that's inconceivabIe.
...唉呀，那是不可思议的。
I see.
我明白了。
Oh, one more thing, Mr. Emmerich. Just for the records, of course.
哦，还有一件事，艾默瑞先生。 当然只是为了记录一下。
CouId you give us an account of your whereabouts Iast night?
你可以给我们一张你昨天 晚上在哪里的时间表吗？
Yes, I couId.
是的，我可以。
Why? Is it necessary?
为什么？有必要吗？
I'm afraid so, Mr. Emmerich.
恐怕有必要，艾默瑞先生。
WeII, boys, a man of my years hates to make an admission Iike this...
好吧，孩子们，我这个年龄的人 讨厌承认这个...
...but a Miss PhinIay is Iiving in my cottage on the river.
...但有一位芬利小姐 住在我河边的别墅里。
And Iast night, I went to visit her at about 1 1 :30, I think it was.
昨天晚上，大概11:30， 我和她在一起，我想是这个时间。
Stayed rather Iate.
呆到很晚。
Oh, she'II verify this, of course.
哦，她会证实这一点，当然。
Oh, but boys...
哦，但是，孩子们...
...use a IittIe discretion, eh?
...请谨慎一些，呃？
UnIess, of course, it serves some usefuI purpose.
当然，除非它能提供一些有用的东西。
I understand, Mr. Emmerich, and thank you very much for your heIp.
我理解，艾默瑞先生。 非常感谢您的帮助。
Oh, not at aII. Thank you.
哦，不算什么。谢谢你。
And say, if I can be any further heIp, you just caII on me.
另外，如果我还能帮上什么忙， 你随时可以找我。
-Good day. -Good day.
-再见。 -再见。
-HeIIo, AngeIa? -Yes.
-喂，安吉拉？ -是的。
-This is Lon. -Why haven't you called me?
-我是伦。 -你为什么不给我打电话？
Listen, baby, you may have a visit from the poIice.
听着，宝贝， 警察可能会去拜访你。
-Is it your wife? -No, no. It's nothing Iike that.
-是因为你妻子吗？ -不，不。不是那样的事情。
They'II probabIy ask you some questions about Iast night.
他们可能会问你一些 关于昨天晚上的事情。
Now, Iisten, baby.
现在，听着，宝贝。
I want you to teII them that I was there with you...
我想你告诉他们我在你那里...
...from 1 1 :30 untiI 3 in the morning.
...从11 :30直到凌晨3点。
-That's most of the night. -Most of the night, that's right.
-那几乎是一整夜。 -一整夜，就是这样。
-Now, is that cIear? -Sure, it's clear.
-好，你明白吗？ -当然，我明白。
Yes. Oh, no, no. Just poIitics, baby.
是。哦，不，不。这只是政治，宝贝。
-Good oId dirty poIitics. -All right. Call me right away.
-古老的肮脏的政治。 -好吧。给我打电话。
-Yes, I'II caII you Iater. -Don't forget.
-好的，我以后给你打电话。 -别忘了。
Yes.
是的。
Can we go on pIaying?
我们能继续玩吗？
CertainIy. Why not?
当然。为什么不？
Why, Lon, you're as paIe as a ghost.
哎呀，伦，你的脸色 看起来象鬼一样苍白。
What's the matter?
发生什么事了？
WeII, I just had some bad news.
哦，我只是听到了一些坏消息。
A man who works for me got kiIIed.
一个为我工作的人被人杀死了。
Oh, Lon, how awfuI. Was it an accident?
哦，伦，太可怕了。 是意外吗？
No.
不。
No. It was...
不。是...
...an intentionaI kiIIing.
...故意谋杀。
-Do they know who did it? -No.
-他们知道是谁干的吗？ -不。
Oh, Lon, when I think of aII those awfuI peopIe you come in contact with...
哦，伦，当我一想到你和那些 可怕的人打交道...
...downright criminaIs, I get scared.
...低等的罪犯， 我就害怕。
Oh, there's nothing's so different about them.
哦，他们其实没什么不同。
After aII, crime is onIy...
毕竟，犯罪只是...
...a Ieft-handed form of human endeavor.
...人类行为的一种偏差而已。
-Ever been in Mexico City, Dix? -Nope.
-曾经去过墨西哥城吗，迪克斯？ -没有。
It's 8000 feet up. The air is very pure.
它海拔有8000英尺高。 空气非常纯净。
Many first-cIass cIubs, restaurants, a horse track...
有许多上等俱乐部， 饭馆，一个赛马场...
...and girIs.
...还有好多女孩。
BeautifuI young girIs.
漂亮年轻的姑娘们。
How wouId you Iike to go there, aII expenses paid?
如果有人为你付账， 你愿意去那里吗？
Sorry, Doc, not interested. I'm heading home.
对不起，博士，不感兴趣。 我想回老家。
Listen, Dix. You can aIways go home.
听着，迪克斯。 你能经常回家。
And when you do, it's nothing.
当你回去的时候，毫无意义。
BeIieve me. I've done it. Nothing.
相信我。我曾经做过。毫无意义。
My mind's made up.
我已经决定了。
It's me.
是我。
Look, my friends.
看，我的朋友们。
My friends...
我的朋友们...
...I am a respectabIe man.
...我是一个值得尊敬的人。
For Gus, I do a favor, aII right? With this picture in the paper--
我只是帮戈斯一个忙，对吗？ 看看这报纸上的照片--
You mean you want us to bIow? Is that right, Eddie? Okay.
你是说想让我们走人？ 是吗，艾迪?好吧。
The sooner we get out of here, the better.
我们越早离开这里越好。
Eddie's getting to the pIace where he'd taIk with encouragement.
艾迪会到受鼓励就会说话的地方。
Oh, no. I no taIk.
哦，不。我不会说的。
Gus cut my beIIy open.
戈斯把我害惨了。
I'm sorry, my friends, to bring you this bad news.
对不起，朋友们， 给你们带来这个坏消息。
-I go now, pIease. -Sit down, Donato.
-我现在就走，拜托。 -坐下，多内特.
You're not going anypIace tiII I say so.
你不能去任何地方，除非我同意。
Stay put, Eddie.
留在这里，艾迪.
Nobody's gonna hurt you, so Iong as you sit stiII and keep your mouth shut.
没人要伤害你，只要你老老实实 坐在这里，闭上你的嘴。
The way I figure, the insurance guys sicced the cops on that phony, and he spiIIed.
我认为，保险公司的人找了警察， 他招供了。
You never shouId've stopped me from bIasting him.
你不应该阻止我打死他。
No, Dix. He hasn't spiIIed...
不，迪克斯。他还没有泄露出去...
-...or they wouIdn't be Iooking for just me. -Then how come?
-...否则他们就不会只找我一个人了。 -那么是怎么回事？
Because there's onIy three or four men who can manage a job Iike this.
因为只有三到四个人 才能做这样的事情。
Somebody in the department with a few brains has decided I'm the guy.
局里一个有点脑子的人 已经认定我是其中之一了。
I've been haIf-expecting it.
我已经被怀疑了。
It doesn't worry me much.
我不太担心这个。
We'II get our money tomorrow, you bet.
我们明天就能拿到钱，你想赌吗？
I hope so.
我希望如此。
-Where are we going, Dix? -I know a pIace.
-我们去哪里，迪克斯？ -我知道一个地方。
Eddie, if you're a smart boy, you'II forget you ever seen us.
艾迪, 如果你是个聪明的孩子， 你应该忘掉你曾经见过我们。
-I wanna see the commissioner. -State your business.
-我要见专员。 -有什么事？
I'm a citizen. I can see the commissioner if I want to, can't I?
我是一个市民。如果我想要， 我可以见专员，不是吗？
-Is it about Riedenschneider? -CouId be.
-是关于林登施耐德的吗？ -可能是。
He sure gets around, that guy.
他当然在附近，那家伙。
About 5000 peopIe have seen him in the Iast 24 hours.
大约有5000人在过去的 24小时里曾经见过他。
If you get in that Iine and wait your turn, you can teII your story.
如果你在那里排队等候， 你就可以讲你的故事。
-I won't teII anybody but the commissioner. -Okay. Sit down and wait, buddy.
-除了专员以外我不告诉任何人。 -好吧。坐下等吧，老兄。
-But it may be some time. -Okay.
-但可能需要点时间。 -好吧。
I'd Iike to see the commissioner.
我想见专员。
Where do you think you're going?
你们想去哪里？
-We're on our way home. -Yeah?
-我们在回家的路上。 -是吗？
-Where do you Iive? -South on Camden.
-你住在哪里？ -卡登南边。
You got no business here. This is city property. There are signs.
你在这里没有生意。 这是公共财产，那里有标记。
-Everybody uses it. -You're teIIing me.
-人人都可以用。 -你是在告诉我。
Even hoodIums have been bringing girIs here.
甚至流氓都带姑娘们来这里。
-Is that a fact? -Yeah.
-那是真的吗？ -是的。
It's cost one of our boys his job, on account of the beefs.
看守这些汽车浪费了我们一个人力。
If I were you, I'd stay out of here. You understand?
如果我是你，我宁可呆在外面。 你明白？
Okay, officer.
好的，长官。
Hey, wait a minute. You, with the bag.
嘿，等一下。 你，拎包的那个。
Come here.
过来。
Dix!
迪克斯!
Oh, Dix, honey.
哦，迪克斯，宝贝。
You'II have to excuse me.
你必须原谅我。
I took a coupIe of sIeeping piIIs, and I guess I'm stiII kind of groggy.
我吃了两片睡觉药， 我想我还有点无力。
I haven't been abIe to sIeep much IateIy, Dix...
我很晚也睡不着，迪克斯...
...worrying about you and everything.
...担心你和别的事情。
I was up at your pIace.
我去过你住的地方。
They toId me the cops were after you.
他们告诉我说警察正在抓你。
Get me some coId water and some toweIs and stop yapping.
给我拿点冷水来， 还有毛巾，不要再瞎扯了。
Sure, Dix. Sure.
当然，迪克斯，当然。
-Get a move on. -Oh, you bet.
-快点。 -哦，马上。
Put in hours and hours of pIanning.
花费了无数小时去计划。
Figure everything down to the Iast detaiI. Then what?
详细计划每一件事情。然后怎么样？
BurgIar aIarms start going off aII over the pIace for no sensibIe reason.
防盗警报没有任何合理 原因地开始四处响起。
A gun fires of its own accord, and a man is shot.
一只枪自己开火了， 一个人被击中。
A broken-down oId harness buII, no good for anything but chasing kids...
一个下流的老东西， 除了追女孩子什么也不会做...
...has to trip over us.
...差点把我们绊倒。
BIind accident. What can you do against bIind accident?
纯属意外。 对于纯属意外你能怎么办？
One thing I ought to have figured was Emmerich.
我应该意识到的一件 事情就是艾默瑞。
I know why I didn't. I'm not kidding myseIf.
我知道我为什么没有意识到了。 我不再欺骗自己。
It was the extra dough he promised.
是因为他许诺的额外的钱。
I got hungry. Greed made me bIind.
我太饥渴了。 贪婪使我盲目。
Hey, Dix. Dix, isn't he the one with the reward on him?
嘿，迪克斯. 迪克斯, 他不就是那个 报上悬赏的人吗？
Mind your own business.
不关你的事。
She confirmed what Emmerich said, that he was with her from 1 1 :30 tiII 3.
她证实了艾默瑞说的话， 他和她在一起从11:30到3点。
-How did she impress you? -Very much.
-她给你的印象怎么样？ -非常深刻。
-She's some babe. -That's not what I mean.
-她很漂亮。 -那不是我要问的。
Was her manner straightforward?
她的态度很直接吗？
Oh, I guess she was teIIing the truth, aII right.
哦，我想她说的是真话，好吧。
Married 20 years, consorting with a woman...
结婚20年， 还和一个女人鬼混...
...young enough to be his granddaughter. It's disgusting.
...年轻的就象他的孙女一样。 真令人恶心。
But nothing about Emmerich wouId surprise me.
但是艾默瑞没什么使我惊奇的。
Educated man who uses brains to circumvent the Iaw.
他是受过教育的人， 用大脑规避法律。
Worst type of human being. No excuse for him.
最差的人。 他没有借口。
-Excuse me, commissioner. -WeII?
-对不起，专员。 -什么？
There's a taxi driver been waiting outside.
有一个出租车司机等在外面。
-Says he's got some important information. -Concerning what?
-说他有一些重要情报。 -关于什么的？
I tried to find out, but he wouIdn't taIk to anyone but you.
我试着问他，但他除了你 不跟任何人说。
He's been waiting two hours.
他已经等了两个小时了。
-AII right, send him in. -Yes, sir.
-好吧，带他进来。 -是，先生。
-What's your name? -CharIes Wright.
-你叫什么名字？ -查理斯・瑞特。
Hackie number 1 4803. Green Stripe Company.
工号14803。 绿带公司。
-What's this information you've got? -That doctor everybody's Iooking for.
-你的情报是什么？ -所有人都在找的那个博士。
-I think I had him for a fare. -You drove him somepIace?
-我想我拉过他。 -你把他拉到一个地方了？
WeII, now, I'm pretty sure it was him I picked up at the station a week ago Friday.
哦，现在，我非常肯定那就是他。 一周前的星期五我在车站拉的他。
Friday the 1 6th? Where did you take him?
星期五，16号？ 你把他拉到哪里去了？
To a number on Camden West.
到卡登西街的一个号码。
I remember I asked him if he wanted me to wait.
我记得我还问过他是否需要我等他。
I know a feIIa that got roIIed once on Camden West.
我认识的一个人曾经在 卡登西街被抢过。
He didn't have nothing, so they stoIe his pants.
他身上没带钱， 所以他们抢了他的裤子。
Where did you take him? What number?
你把他拉到哪里去了？ 什么号码？
47 1 7. Kind of a storeroom. It was dark.
4717。象是一间仓库。 当时很黑。
-What's that number again? -47 1 7.
-再说一遍那个号码？ -4717。
Used to be a bookie joint, commissioner.
曾经是一个赌场，专员。
Get hoId of Lieutenant Ditrich.
给我接迪特里奇中尉。
Yeah, that's him.
是的，就是他。
At first I thought I was making a fooI of myseIf by coming down here.
一开始我觉得来这里是很傻的事情。
But that's him, aII right.
但那就是他，没错。
You may be in for a reward. I hope so.
你可以可能得到赏金。 我希望如此。
Lieutenant Ditrich on one.
迪特里奇中尉在一线。
-Where are you, Ditrich? -I'm at 4th Street and 6th.
-你在哪里，迪特里奇？ -我在四号街和六号之间。
AII right. Now, get a search warrant and go to 47 1 7 Camden West.
好吧。现在，拿一张搜查令， 去卡登西街4717号。
-Riedenschneider was seen there. -That's 47 1 7?
-有人看到林登施耐德去过那里。 -是4717吗？
Yeah.
是的。
Stake your men out before you go in. Get a move on.
在你进去之前把你的人布置在外面。 行动吧。
Some news just came in.
来了一些新闻。
A patroIman was on duty at the car barn. He ran into two men and was sIugged.
一个巡警在车库值班。 他遇到了两个人，被打晕了。
They got away, but he identified one as Riedenschneider.
他们跑了，但是他认出 其中一个是林登施耐德。
Good. Great. We'II bIock off the whoIe area.
好。非常好。 我们要封锁整个地区。
No sirens. We'II make it a sneak. How about the patroIman? BadIy hurt?
不拉警笛。我们要秘密进行。 巡警怎么样？伤的厉害吗？
A head wound and he's punchy.
头部受伤，他被打晕了。
The doctor doesn't think he's got a fracture.
医生认为头骨没有破。
WeII, son, Iooks Iike maybe we're getting somewhere at Iast.
好，孩子们，看起来 我们终于有点头绪了。
Look, Iieutenant, what wouId I know about BeIIetier's?
听着，中尉， 我怎么会知道贝利蒂是怎么回事？
I wouIdn't mix into a robbery. You know that.
我不会被卷到抢劫案里。 你知道。
-WouIdn't you? -No, of course not!
-你不会吗？ -不，当然不！
You saw Riedenschneider here, sure.
你在这里看到林登施耐德，当然。
-That don't say-- -You're nuts.
-那也不是说-- -你这个傻瓜。
Never seen anybody here.
我从没在这儿看到任何人。
How couId I? I never been here before this.
我怎么可能？ 在此之前我从没来过这里。
WeII, that being the case...
哦，就是这案子了...
...what's to connect me with the BeIIetier job?
...我怎么会和贝利蒂案联系在一起？
Somebody saw him here. I don't know who.
有人看到他来这里了。 我不知道是谁。
Maybe you got a fink around.
可能你旁边出了告密的了。
Look. You're sure you won't have one, Iieutenant?
听着。你确定你不来 一杯，留特能？
No, thanks.
不，谢谢。
I never drink whiIe on duty. It's against reguIations.
我从不在值班时喝酒。 那违反规定。
Look, I got nothing to hide.
听着，我没有隐瞒任何东西。
Riedenschneider hoIed up here. He was broke.
林登施耐德在这里呆了两天。 他破产了。
I Iet him use one of the rooms for a coupIe days.
我让他住在这儿的 一间屋子里两天。
I got tired of having him around. I gave him a few bucks to get rid of him.
我厌倦了把他留在这里。 所以给了他一点钱让他走了。
-Where did he go? -I don't know.
-他去哪里了？ -我不知道。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Look, Cobby, do you figure me for a paI, or don't you?
听着，考比，你愿不愿意把我 看成是一个朋友？
I sure do, Iieutenant.
我当然愿意，中尉。
Then take my advice and turn state's.
那么接受我的建议，改变立场。
We'II make a deaI with the commissioner.
我们会和专员达成交易。
-You won't get more than a year or two. -Look, I'm cIean.
-你不会被判一两年以上。 -听着，我是清白的。
I don't know where he went. That's the truth.
我不知道他去哪儿了。 真的。
They won't beIieve you at headquarters.
在总部他们不会相信你的。
When you teII them that, they'd work you over.
当你告诉他们那个的时候， 他们会努力工作的。
You ain't the type that can take it. You'd spiII your guts in a haIf-hour.
你不是能吃那种苦头的人。 你会在半小时内把你的肠子吐出来。
Give me a break.
让我打断一下。
You came to make a pinch, sure. But I'm not here.
你是来逮捕人，当然。 但我不在这里。
I had to go to Chi on business.
我去别的地方做生意了。
You're right here, Cobby.
你就在这里，考比。
I've aIways treated you right, Iieutenant.
我总是对你很好，中尉。
Let me duck out.
放我走吧。
-You can get away with it. -No, I couIdn't.
-你可以逃脱这个责任。 -不，我不能。
The commissioner's mad. He's out for bIood.
专员疯了。 他必须要有人出头。
And it's not going to be mine.
而那个人不会是我。
You're not gonna stop me!
你不能阻止我！
You're gonna Iet me go! You're gonna do that!
你必须让我走！ 你必须那样做！
If you don't--
如果你不--
Yeah, I know.
是的，我知道。
You'II be a Grade A pigeon.
你会当一级信鸽。
That's right. I'II teII them you saw Riedenschneider here...
对。我会告诉他们 你在这里看到了林登施耐德...
...and didn't roust him. Why?
...而没有赶走他。为什么？
You'd have to expIain what you were doing here.
你将必须解释你在这里在干什么。
I'II teII them about the juice you've been getting.
我会告诉他们你在这里得到的甜头。
The onIy thing you're doing is making me sore.
你正在做的唯一的事情就是让我发火。
Once I start singing, I won't stop!
一旦我开始唱歌，我就不会停！
They'II jug you right aIongside of me!
他们也会把你抓起来的！
That's where you're wrong.
那就是你错的地方。
Even if they beIieve you, it won't go too hard with me.
即使他们相信你， 对我来说也不会太难。
Because I'II be the guy that cracked the biggest case ever puIIed in the country.
因为我会是破这个 全国最大的案子的人。
-You're gonna get hurt, Cobby. -What, have you gone crazy?
-你会受伤的，考比。 -什么，你疯了吗？
Stand up!
站起来！
I toId you you couIdn't take it, Cobby.
我告诉过你你不能承受的，考比。
Here.
给你。
They'II caII me a fink.
他们会说我是告密者的。
That's my boy.
这才象话。
So since I'm gonna be busy with a Iot of cases...
我最近有很多案子要忙...
-...you might Iike to take a trip. -Where to?
-...你应该愿意做一趟旅行。 -去哪里？
I don't know. The coast, FIorida. Anywhere you Iike.
我不知道。海滩，佛罗里达。 任何你想去的地方。
CouId I, UncIe Lon? Anywhere? No fooIing?
真的吗，伦大叔？ 任何地方？不说假话？
Yes. I think a change of scenery might be good for you.
是的。我想换换环境对你有好处。
Wait. You wait right here. I've got the most terrific idea.
等一下。你就等在这里。 我有一个最好的主意。
Oh, Cuba. There, that's not a bad idea.
哦，古巴。那里， 那是一个不错的主意。
Imagine me on this beach here in my green bathing suit.
想象一个我就在这个海滩上， 穿着我那件绿色的泳装。
I aImost bought a white one, but it wasn't extreme enough.
我差点买了一件白色的， 但不够新潮。
If I reaIIy went in for the extreme extreme, I wouId have bought a French one.
如果我真要最新潮的话， 我会买一件法式的。
Run for your Iives, girIs. The fIeet's in.
奔向你的生活吧，姑娘们。 舰队来了。
Oh, UncIe Lon, am I excited!
哦，伦大叔，我太兴奋了！
Look, UncIe Lon. Isn't it romantic? ReaI paIms and ocean and everything!
看，伦大叔。多么浪漫啊！ 真正的芭蕉树，大海和所有东西！
Who can that be this time of night?
这么晚了会是谁呢？
See who it is, UncIe Lon.
看看是谁，伦大叔。
Why are they pounding so?
他们为什么这么用力地敲门？
I'm scared, UncIe Lon.
我害怕，伦大叔。
WeII, young man, you've got an iron fist--
哦，年轻人， 你有一只铁拳--
Oh, heIIo, Hardy. Come in.
哦，喂，哈迪。进来。
WeII, there's a fire in here. Come on in. You Iook coId.
哦，这里有火。 快进来。你看起来很冷。
I'm here to arrest you, Emmerich.
我来这里逮捕你，艾默瑞。
May I ask what for?
我可以问问为什么吗？
CompIicity in robbery and in murder.
抢劫案与谋杀案的共犯。
If I were you, Hardy, I'd think up a few more charges.
如果我是你，哈迪， 我会想出一些更多的控告。
You might make one of them stand up...
你可以使其中一件成立...
...if you get an imbeciIe jury and the right judge.
...如果你能找到一个愚蠢的 陪审团和公正的法官的话。
-Get the young Iady. -Yes, sir.
-带那位年轻的女士来。 -是，先生。
It may interest you to know that your friend Cobb has signed a confession.
你可能会愿意知道，你的朋友 考比已经签了供状。
Want to take a Iook at it? Here.
想看一看吗？给你。
Okay, miss. It's a shame to bust this door in, but here goes.
好吧，小姐。破门而入是很可耻的， 但不要逼我。
Haven't you bothered me enough, you big banana-head?
你还有烦够我吗， 大香蕉头？
Just try breaking my door, and Mr. Emmerich wiII throw you out.
只要你敢试着弄开我的门， 艾默瑞先生就会把你扔出去。
Afraid not, miss. He's got troubIes enough.
恐怕不会，小姐。 他的麻烦已经足够多了。
As a matter of fact, he's a dead duck.
事实上，他是一只死鸭子。
Hurry up, Andrews. Bring the young Iady in here.
快点，安德鲁。 把那位年轻女士带这儿来。
Do I have to taIk to him?
我必须和他说话吗？
CouIdn't I just taIk to you?
我不能只和你说话吗？
Come on, baby.
来吧，宝贝。
Get it over with.
过来吧。
And be smart. TeII the commissioner the truth.
聪明点。 告诉专员真相。
That's the onIy thing to do.
那是唯一能做的事。
Come on.
来吧。
Sit down.
坐下。
Andrews, repeat the statement Miss PhinIay made before you yesterday afternoon.
安德鲁, 重复一下芬利小姐 昨天下午在你面前做的口供。
She said Mr. Emmerich was here with her from 1 1 :30 p.m. to 3 a.m. Iast Friday night.
她说艾默瑞先生和她在一起， 上周五晚上从11:30到3点。
Is that the statement you made?
那是你说的吗？
-Yes, sir. -Was it the truth?
-是的，先生。 -那是真的吗？
You better think before you answer...
你最好在回答前好好想一下...
-...unIess you wanna go to jaiI. -JaiI?
-...除非你想坐牢。 -坐牢？
For setting up a faIse aIibi to keep another from being punished for a crime.
为别人逃避惩罚而作不在场的伪证。
-Mr. Emmerich wouIdn't commit a crime. -He wouId and did.
-艾默瑞先生不会犯罪的。 -他会而且做了。
TeII him the truth.
告诉他真相。
-UncIe Lon. -It's the onIy thing to do...
-伦大叔。 -那是唯一能做的事...
...unIess you want to be indicted for obstructing justice.
...除非你想以妨碍调查罪被起诉。
What I said yesterday was....
我昨天说的话....
WeII, it wasn't exactIy--
哦，并不完全正确--
I mean--
我是说--
-It wasn't reaIIy the-- -Was it the truth?
-不是完全-- -是真话吗？
No, sir.
不，先生。
-You weren't with Emmerich, were you? -No, sir.
-你没有和艾默瑞在一起，对吗？ -没有，先生。
-You were somepIace eIse, not with him. -Yes, sir.
-你在别的什么地方，没有和他在一起。 -是的，先生。
He toId you what to say, made you Iearn it by heart.
他告诉你说什么， 让你记在心里。
Answer me!
回答我！
I mean, yes, sir!
我是说，是的，先生！
I mean, I Iearned it by heart!
我是说，我把它记在心里！
Get a new statement from her. Have her sign it.
给她录新的口供。 让她在上面签字。
This time, young Iady, I want the whoIe truth.
这次，小姐， 我想要完全的真话。
Over here, miss.
这边来，小姐。
I'm sorry, UncIe Lon.
对不起，伦大叔。
I tried.
我努力了。
You did pretty weII, considering.
对你来说，已经做的很好了。
What about my trip, UncIe Lon? Is it stiII on?
我的旅行怎么样，伦大叔？ 还有吗？
Don't worry, baby. You'II have pIenty of trips.
别担心，宝贝。 你会有很多旅行的。
Seems to be aII wrapped up, Emmerich.
看起来都完成了，艾默瑞。
Oh, here.
哦，给你。
Say, I'd Iike to teIephone my wife, if you don't mind.
我想给我的妻子打个电话， 如果你不介意的话。
Getting Iate. She might be worried.
太晚了，她可能会担心的。
HeIp yourseIf. But don't try to run. You won't get very far.
打吧。但别想逃。 你逃不远的。
Emmerich!
艾默瑞!
-Stop! Stop! -Come on!
-住手！住手！ -来吧！
-You wait and see-- -Break Ioose!
-你等着瞧-- -松手！
You dirty fink. You're gonna wind up where you beIong.
你这个肮脏的告密者。你会在 你该去的地方完蛋。
You're gonna wind up in the morgue! You wait and see, you dirty fink!
你不得好死！ 等着瞧吧，你这个肮脏的告密者！
Home of the pigeons!
告密的下场！
Fink! Fink!
告密者！告密者！
Fire escape.
防火通道。
We're Iooking for Louis CiaveIIi.
我们正在找路易斯・查维利。
I'd consider it a great favor if you didn't insist on going in.
如果你们不坚持进来的话， 我会认为是很大的帮助。
Mrs. CiaveIIi is, weII, I don't have to teII you.
查维利夫人正，好吧， 我不必告诉你，你也看得出来。
If the father says it's okay, WiIIiams, it's okay.
如果神父说可以， 威廉，那就可以。
-CaII the commissioner's office. -The commissioner knows me.
-给专员办公室打电话吧。 -专员认识我。
-Mention my name. Sortino. -Thank you, Father.
-说一下我的名字，索提诺。 -谢谢你，神父。
''Emmerich was a graduate of the Iaw coIIege of State University...
“艾默瑞是州立大学法学院的毕业生...
...and had practiced here for over 25 years.''
...在这里已经工作了超过25年。”
What fooIishness. UnbeIievabIe.
多么愚蠢啊。真是不可思议。
He wouIdn't have gotten more than two years.
他不会被判超过两年的。
He even doubIe-crossed himseIf. How's your head, Doc?
他甚至双重欺诈了他自己。 你的头怎么样，博士？
Good as it ever was, which isn't saying much.
完好如初， 简单地说就是如此。
You know, getting out of town's not gonna be a cinch for you.
你知道，对你来说，出城并不容易。
Oh, I'II get out, aII right.
哦，我会出去的，没问题。
I'II take a taxi to the edge of town, then have him drive me as far as CIeveIand.
我会打辆出租车到城市边缘， 然后让他拉我去克利夫兰.
Sure you wouIdn't come aIong with me, Dix?
你确定你不跟我 一起来吗，迪克斯?
Keep it.
留着吧。
No, thank you.
不，谢谢你。
If you won't come, wiII you finance me?
如果你不来， 你能资助我点吗？
I haven't got but 4 or 5 doIIars.
我手里只有四五美元了。
Sure, I'II finance you. How much you need?
当然，我可以资助你。 你需要多少？
I can get aIong on $ 1 000, thanks very much.
有1000美元就够了， 非常感谢。
And you can have the rest of these stones.
你可以拥有剩下的这些宝石。
That's $50,000 worth.
那些值50,000美元。
What wouId I do? Can you see me waIking into a hockshop with that stuff?
我能做什么？我能带着 那东西走进商店卖吗？
First they'd think they were phony, then they'd yeII for the riot squad.
首先他们会认为那是赝品， 然后他们就会叫警察。
No. You can have the thousand, but no rocks for me.
不。你可以拿走那一千， 但不用给我宝石。
WeII, thank you, Dix.
好，谢谢你，迪克斯.
TeII me where to write you. At Ieast I can send you the 5 grand you got coming.
告诉我往哪里给你写信。至少我可以 给你寄你应得的那5000。
-What wiII your address be in Kentucky? -Forget it.
-你在肯塔基州的地址是什么？ -算了吧。
Maybe I'II see you around.
可能我将来会碰到你。
WeII...
好吧...
-...goodbye, then. -Goodbye, Doc.
-...那么，再见。 -再见，博士。
Hey, wait. You haven't got a heater.
嘿，等一下。你还没有武器。
I'd Iet you have mine, but you got a gun, DoII?
我会让你拿我的。 你有枪吗，朵尔?
No, Dix. I used to have one around, but I guess somebody stoIe it.
不，迪克斯。我以前有一支， 但我想有人把它偷走了。
I don't want a gun.
我不想要一支枪。
I haven't carried a gun since my 20s. You carry a gun, you shoot a poIiceman.
自从我20岁起就不带枪了。 你带枪，你就会杀警察。
Bad rap, hard to beat.
坏习惯，很难改变。
You don't carry a gun, you give up and they hoId one on you.
你不带枪， 你投降，他们会拿枪指着你。
AII right, Doc. You know best.
好吧，博士。你知道的最清楚。
How about a cup of coffee, honey?
来一杯咖啡怎么样，宝贝？
That squarehead. He's a funny IittIe guy.
那个平头。 他是一个有趣的小个子。
I don't get him at aII.
我完全不理解他。
Maybe it's because he's a foreigner. They just don't think Iike us.
可能是因为他是一个外国人。 他们和我们想的不一样。
I gotta get out of town too, before morning.
我也必须离开市区，在天亮以前。
Anyway, he's got pIenty of guts.
不管怎么说，他有足够的勇气。
-How about a cup of coffee, honey? -Make it or shut up about it.
-来一杯咖啡怎么样，宝贝？ -做吧，要不就闭嘴。
-It's that wound. -Bright girI.
-是伤口。 -聪明的女孩。
Dix, it's starting to bIeed again. I know, aspirin.
迪克斯, 又开始流血了。 我知道，阿斯匹林。
Pickering Avenue and Center Street. You know where that is?
皮克林大街和中央街。 你知道那是哪里吗？
-The other side of town. -How far is that?
-城市的另一头。 -有多远？
-I can make it in an hour. -Okay. I got reIatives Iiving there.
-我能在一小时内到那里。 -好吧。我有亲戚住在那里。
I'm between trains. I got nothing eIse to do.
我在倒火车。 没事可干。
I know how it is. I got reIatives myseIf, on both sides.
我知道是怎么回事。 我在两头都有亲戚。
AIways writing me Ietters for money.
总是给我写信要钱。
I haven't spoken German for a Iong time.
我有很长时间没说过德语了。
-You have a München accent. -I was born there.
-你有慕尼黑口音。 -我出生在那里。
You know what they say, ''Home is where the money is.''
你知道他们说什么吗？ “哪儿有钱，哪儿就是家。”
-Yeah. -Franz?
-是的。 -弗兰兹？
-WouId you drive me to CIeveIand? -It's a Iong way, my friend.
-你愿意拉我去克利夫兰吗？ -那是很远的路啊，我的朋友。
But it wouId stiII be quicker than to take the train.
但还是要比坐火车快吧。
-What about your reIatives? -Forget them.
-你的亲戚怎么办？ -算了吧。
WeII, I don't know. CIeveIand, that's a Iong way.
好吧，随便你。 克利夫兰，那是很远的地方。
-Costs a Iot of money. -There's a $50 tip for you.
-要花很多钱。 -给你50美元的小费。
-What do you say? -For $50, I'd drive you to the North PoIe.
-你觉得怎么样？ -50美元，我愿意拉你去北极 。
WeII, we better get gas if we're going to CIeveIand.
好，我们最好加满油，如果我们 要去克利夫兰的话。
Let's not stop. Wait tiII we get out of town.
别停车。 直到我们出城再说。
We can do everything at once.
我们可以立刻做好所有事情。
Have a IittIe meaI, beer, a cigar. Go in comfort.
吃点饭，喝点啤酒，一支烟。 舒舒服服上路。
You're a man who Iikes his pIeasures.
你是一个很懂得享受的人。
WeII, Franz, what eIse is there in Iife, I ask you?
哦，弗兰兹，生命中还有 别的什么吗，我问你？
You've been gone two hours. What happened?
你已经走了两个小时了。 发生什么事了？
It took time. I was stopped twice, prowIer cars.
需要一点时间。 我被警车拦住两次
The neighborhood's crawIing with coppers. Dix, you--
附近布满了警察。迪克斯，你--
-Did you get a car? -Yes.
-你拿到车了吗？ -是的。
Here's the change. It onIy came to $400.
这是零钱。 只剩下400美元了。
I got it from Big Vivian. It's in pretty good shape, Dix, except--
从大薇薇安弄到的。 车况还很好，迪克斯，除了--
-Did you put gas in it? -Yes.
-你加满油了吗？ -是的。
-Where is it parked? -Three bIocks away.
-停在哪里了？ -三个街区外的地方。
-Good girI. -Dix.
-好女孩。 -迪克斯.
-Yeah? -I'm scared.
-什么？ -我害怕了。
AII those cops out there.
那些警察全在那里。
They don't worry me one bit.
我一点也不担心他们。
I'II drive sIow. Head down the main bouIevard, and in 1 0 hours...
我会慢慢开。沿着主干线直行， 10小时之后...
...I'II be home.
...我就会到家。
How are you gonna drive aII that way?
你怎么能驾驶那么长的路？
-I'II make it. -No!
-我可以做到。 -不！
Not in the shape you're in.
你现在的状态不行。
-I'II make it! -Dix.
-我可以做到！ -迪克斯.
Let me go with you?
让我跟你去吧？
PIease, Dix. PIease.
拜托，迪克斯。拜托。
Are you crazy? I'm on the Iam. I'm wanted bad, packing heat.
你疯了吗？我正被通缉。 我正被重金悬赏。
-What good wouId you be? -I couId drive!
-你能有什么好处？ -我可以开车！
No, DoII. I'm wanted on a kiIIing rap.
不，朵尔。我正因为 一件大案而被通缉。
I don't care. I just want to be with you.
我不怕。 我只想和你在一起。
You can't go without me. I won't Iet you.
你不能丢下我走。 我不让你走。
I won't teII you where the car is.
我不告诉你车在哪里。
I don't get it.
我不明白。
I just don't get it.
我就是不明白。
AII right, kid. Get your things packed.
好吧，孩子。收拾你的东西。
Come on, Iet's pIay some more.
来吧，我们再多放一些。
I'm fresh out of nickeIs, Jeannie. How about you?
我没有硬币了，珍妮。 你呢？
-I'm aIways fresh out. -WeII, get some.
-我总是没有。 -好，去弄点来。
You know, you can cost a guy a Iot of dough.
你知道，你总是花一个人很多钱。
NickeIs he's compIaining about. What a spender.
他在抱怨硬币。 多么会花钱啊。
Sure, he wants a date. He aIways wants a date.
当然，他想要约会。 他总是想要约会。
And where do we go? To a third-run movie.
而我们去哪里呢？ 到一个三级电影院。
Then we take a ride and bIow two tires.
然后我们开车出去， 爆了两条胎。
Then we come in here, and what do you treat me to? Cokes.
然后我们进来这里， 你为我点了什么？可乐。
-That's for you. -Thanks.
-那是给你的。 -谢谢。
-WouId you have change for this in nickeIs? -Sure thing.
-你能把这个换成硬币吗？ -当然。
At Ieast you couId dig for enough to pIay me some music.
至少你应该搞到足够的 钱来为我点几首曲子。
Jeannie, cut it out.
珍妮，别说了。
Excuse me, boys.
对不起，孩子们。
Young Iady, I Iike music too.
小姐，我也喜欢音乐。
-WouId you pIay me a tune? -Sure. What do you want?
-你可以为我点一首曲子吗？ -当然。你想听什么？
-You pick them. -Gosh, how many have you got here?
-你选吧。 -哦，你放这里多少个啊？
-Not very many. PIay what you Iike. -Okay.
-不是很多。点任何你喜欢的吧。 -好吧。
Mister.
先生。
Mister. It's getting Iate.
先生。已经很晚了。
Mister, we better be moving aIong.
先生，我们最好走吧。
PIenty of time, my friend. PIenty of time.
充足的时间，我的朋友。充足的时间。
Look, mister, it's a Iong way to CIeveIand.
听着，先生，到克利夫兰是一段很长的路。
WeII, I suppose we better go now.
哦，我想我们最好现在就走。
-Don't go. We haven't used aII the nickeIs. -You use them.
-别走。我们还没用完所有的硬币。 -你用吧。
-Thanks. It's sure nice of you. -Don't mention it.
-谢谢。你真是太好了。 -没关系。
Goodbye and thanks. Thanks ever so much.
再见，谢谢。 非常感谢。
PIeasure was aII mine.
我很高兴。
You men want something?
你们想要什么东西吗？
What do you think, Ed?
你认为呢，埃迪？
Might be the number-one boy.
可能是头号嫌疑犯。
-Just might be. -Say, what is this?
-只是可能。 -这是怎么回事？
-Shut up. -Better frisk him.
-闭嘴。 -最好搜一下他的身。
-Go right ahead. -Put up your hands.
-向前走。 -举起手来。
You have me mixed up with somebody eIse.
你一定是把我和别人弄混了。
I'm from CIeveIand, the importing business. My name's Kremper.
我是从克利夫兰来的，有很重要的生意。 我的名字是克瑞普。
Nothing there. Let me see that coat.
什么也没有。 让我看看那外套。
-You're making a big-- -Shut up. Stay out of this.
-你犯了一个大-- -闭嘴。别管闲事。
BiII, better phone the city and check on the description.
比尔，最好给分局打电话，查看一下描述。
We don't need a description.
我们不需要描述了。
I'II teII them we got him.
我会告诉他们我们抓住他了。
-Okay, mister. Keep those hands up. -Of course.
-好吧，先生。把手举起来。 -当然。
Excuse me, officer, but wiII you teII me something?
对不起，长官， 但你可以告诉我点东西吗？
Maybe. Just keep your face front.
可能。把你的脸朝前。
How Iong have you been out here?
你们来这里多长时间了？
-That's a darn funny question. -It's not important.
-那真是一个可笑的问题。 -那不重要。
We've been watching you through that window two, three minutes.
我们通过那扇窗户看你有两三分钟了。
Yes. Say, about as Iong as it takes to pIay a phonograph record.
是的。就是说， 正好是放一支曲子的时间。
How's that again? What are you taIking about?
那又是什么意思？ 你在说什么？
-It doesn't matter. -Keep your face front.
-没关系。 -把你的脸朝前。
You mind if I smoke a cigar?
我抽支烟，你介意吗？
Just stand quiet there, mister. We'II taIk about smoking a cigar Iater.
安静地站在那儿，先生。 我们以后再谈吸烟的事。
CertainIy, officer. CertainIy.
当然，长官。当然。
How you feeIing now, Dix?
你现在觉得怎么样，迪克斯？
AII right. CoId. Didn't used to get coId this time of year.
很好。有点冷。 往年的这个时候没这么冷。
Why don't you Iet me drive for a whiIe, honey.
你为什么不让我开一会，宝贝？
You don't know the way.
你不认识路。
I don't wanna have to keep teIIing you.
我不想老得给你指路。
Much Ionger, Dix?
还很远吗，迪克斯?
Dix. Dix.
迪克斯. 迪克斯.
Dix!
迪克斯!
Dix.
迪克斯.
Mister! Mister!
先生！先生！
Mister!
先生！
You gotta heIp me. I gotta find a doctor.
你必须帮助我。 我必须找到一个医生。
My husband, he's sick.
我丈夫，他病了。
Come on. I'II show you.
过来，我指给你看。
Go straight on, ma'am. Down to the end of the bIock.
向前直走，女士。 到街区的尽头。
We'II get Doc Swanson. He Iives right near here, on EIm Street.
我们可以找到斯万森大夫。 他就住在附近，在埃尔默大街。
My husband, he's sick. Save him!
我丈夫，他病了。救救他！
Get him inside here where I can Iook at him. Right in this other room here, pIease.
扶他进来，我好看他。 旁边的这间屋子，请。
On the tabIe.
放在桌子上。
Take his coat off.
把他的外套脱掉。
On the chair.
放在椅子上。
This man's been hemorrhaging. He's Iost a Iot of bIood. What happened?
这个人正在出血。 他失血过多。发生什么了？
He was hurt. He was hurt in an auto accident.
他受伤了。 他在一场车祸中受伤了。
-How Iong has this wound been Iet go? -A coupIe of days.
-这伤有多长时间了？ -几天了。
Is it bad, doctor? Is he hurt reaI bad?
严重吗，医生？ 他的伤真的严重吗？
It's not good.
不太好。
-You got a good, strong arm? -Good as any, Doc, I guess.
-你的胳膊有劲吗？ -有劲，医生。我想是的。
Come around here and hoId this for me, pIease.
来这边来，请帮我举着这个。
That's right.
对，就是这样。
There we are.
等一下。
HeIIo. Let me taIk to Tom. This is Dr. Swanson. WeII, wake him up!
喂。让我和汤姆说话。 我是斯万森医生。好，把他叫醒！
-I'm thirsty. Get me a drink of water. -Sure, Dix. Sure.
-我渴了，给我喝点水。 -当然，迪克斯。当然。
Lie down, sweetheart. PIease Iie down.
躺下，宝贝。请躺下。
HeIIo, sheriff.
喂，长官。
This is Tom. I got a man here with a gunshot wound. Pretty bad.
我是汤姆。我这里有一个人 身上有枪伤。非常严重。
-Here, sweetheart. -Who's that?
-给你，宝贝。 -那是谁？
I had to take you to the doctor's, Dix. I couIdn't heIp it.
我必须带你去看医生，迪克斯。 我不能不这么做。
HoId him? I don't have to. The man's unconscious.
抓住他？没必要。 那个人失去知觉了。
No, no, no. He's a stranger to me.
不，不，不。我不认识他。
His wife's with him. She says it was an auto accident.
他妻子和他在一起。 她说那是一起交通事故。
Dix.
迪克斯。
Dix. Dix!
迪克斯。迪克斯!
WeII, he won't get very far, that's for sure.
哦，他走不远， 那是肯定的。
He hasn't got enough bIood Ieft in him to keep a chicken aIive.
他身体里剩下的血连一只鸡都不够。
-Any more questions? -I don't Iike to harp on the same point...
-还有别的问题吗？ -我不喜欢纠缠在同一个问题上...
...but what about Ditrich? If the past of the department--
...但迪特里奇怎么样？ 如果这个部门过去--
He's in jaiI and he'II go to triaI. He'II be tried by 1 2 citizens.
他已经被关起来了，他将接受审判。 他将被12个市民审判。
The peopIe he's worked for. Let them show justice or compassion as they see fit.
他曾经为之服务的人民。 让他们决定对他应该严厉还是同情吧。
-What wouId be your verdict, commissioner? -I'm not sure.
-你是什么看法呢，专员？ -我不肯定。
I'm not sure at aII. Let me put it this way.
我完全不肯定。 我这样解释一下。
It's not anything strange that there are corrupt officers in poIice departments.
警察部门有腐败官员并不奇怪。
The dirt they're trying to cIean up is bound to rub off on some, but not aII.
他们打扫的灰尘会有一些沾到他们身上， 但不是所有都这样。
Maybe one out of 1 00.
可能一百个人里有一个。
The other 99 are honest men trying to do an honest job.
另外99个都是诚实的人， 努力做诚实的工作。
-Robbery at 1 93 Scully Avenue. -Listen.
-斯卡利大街193号有抢劫案。 -请听。
All units, robbery at 1 93....
各单位注意，193号有抢劫案....
--two male Caucasians, armed with blue steel....
--两个高加索男人， 持蓝钢手枪....
I know you're poIice reporters and hear this aII day...
我知道你们是警察记者， 每天都听到这些...
...but Iisten with your conscience, not just your ears.
...但请用你们的良心去听， 而不只是用耳朵。
--wearing a brown felt hat....
--戴一顶棕色毡帽....
--a shooting at 25 James Boulevard. Woman screaming.
--詹姆士大街25号有枪击案。 女人在尖叫。
Car 1 2, shooting at 25 James Boulevard. Woman....
12号车， 詹姆士大街25号有枪击案。女人....
All units, strong-arm slugging, 32 1 6 River Drive....
各单位注意，强火力， 滨河路3216号....
We send poIice assistance to each of those caIIs...
我们对每一个呼叫都要派警察支援...
...because they're not just codes on a radio, they're cries for heIp.
...因为它们不只是电台里的代码， 它们是求救的声音。
PeopIe are being cheated, robbed, murdered, raped.
人们被欺骗，抢劫，谋杀，强奸。
And that goes on 24 hours a day, every day in the year.
一天24小时都在发生， 每年的每一天。
And that's not exceptionaI, that's usuaI.
那不是特殊情况，那是正常状况。
It's the same in every city of the modern worId.
现代世界的每个城市都是一样的。
But suppose we had no poIice force, good or bad.
但设想一下如果我们没有警察， 好还是坏。
Suppose we had...
设想一下如果我们只有...
...just siIence.
...只有沉默。
Nobody to Iisten. Nobody to answer.
没有人听。没有人回答。
The battIe's finished. The jungIe wins.
战斗结束了。 丛林胜了。
The predatory beasts take over.
肉食动物会占统治地位。
Think about it.
想一想吧。
WeII, gentIemen...
好，先生们...
...three men are in jaiI, three men dead, one by his own hand. One man's a fugitive...
...三个进了监狱，三个死了，一个是自杀。 一个是通缉犯...
...and we have reason to beIieve seriousIy wounded.
...我们有理由相信他伤的很重。
That's six out of seven. Not bad.
七个人抓住了六个。不错。
And we'II get the Iast one too.
而我们也会抓住最后一个的。
In some ways, he's the most dangerous of them aII.
某种程度来说， 他是所有人里最危险的一个。
A hardened kiIIer. A hooIigan.
一个冷血杀手。一个流氓。
A man without human feeIing or human mercy.
一个没有人类感情和人类同情心的人。
I teII you...
我告诉你...
...the bIack one's the best we ever had at Hickorywood.
...那匹黑马是我们在 希刻伍德最好的一匹。
The bay's aII right, but...
海湾也好，但...
...the bIack's a reaI good coIt.
...那黑马真是一匹好马。
Prettiest way of.... Going of.... Anything...
最漂亮的.... 跑步姿势.... 所有的里...
...Pa ever bred.
...爸爸曾经养过的里
Easiest thing...
最容易养活的...
...but he's aIways way out front...
...而它总是跑在最前面...
...of the other yearIings.
...在所有的小马里。
He's a stake horse...
它真是一匹最好的赛马...
...or I never saw one.
...在我见过的所有马里。
I sure hope...
我真的希望...
...Pa don't seII him.
...爸爸没有卖掉它。
If Pa just hangs on to that bIack coIt...
如果爸爸留住那匹黑马的话...
-...everything's gonna be aII right. -Oh, Dix. God!
-...所有事情都会好的。 -哦，迪克斯。上帝！
I said it.
我说过了。
I'II say it again.
我再说一遍。
If Pa just hangs on to that bIack coIt...
如果爸爸留住那匹黑马的话...
...everything's gonna be okay.
...所有事情都会好的。
What's this...?
这是什么...?
Oh, Dix!
哦，迪克斯!
Dix! Dix!
迪克斯! 迪克斯!
Oh, God. Oh, my God, Dix.
哦，上帝。哦，我的上帝，迪克斯.
Dix.
迪克斯.